. >> GOOD AFTERNOON WELCOME TO
THE JUNE 2ND, 2026 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. >> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL? THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER
FIELDER NOT PRESENT SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MENDELSOHN PRESENT MANDEL MIN PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR
MELGAR MELGAR PRESENTS SUPERVISOR SAUTER SADR PRESENT
SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERRELL PRESENT SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR HUANG WONG PRESENT MR.
PRESIDENT YOU HAVE A QUORUM. >> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK THE
SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT
WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE RAW MATERIALS
WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PENINSULA. AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF
THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE
PARAMETERS OF LEARNING HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST NOR FORGOTTEN
THEIR RESPONSIBLE PARTIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
TERRITORY. AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE
BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELANDS.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS,
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE RAMAKRISHNA LEARNING COMMUNITY
AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST
PEOPLES. >> COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME
IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE?
>> I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG OF THE UNITED STATES OF
AMERICA AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH IT STANDS ONE NATION
UNDER GOD INDIVISIBLE WITH THE LIBERTY AND JUSTICE.
>> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF
AT S.F. GOV TV TODAY THAT IS ESPECIALLY JAMES KAWANA.
THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETINGS AND MAKE THE
TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE PUBLIC ONLINE.
>> MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY COMMUNICATIONS?
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOU ALL TO BE HERE IN ATTENDANCE IN THE
BOARD'S LEGISLATIVE CHAMBER. AND WHEN YOU'RE NOT ABLE TO BE
HERE, YOU CAN WATCH THE PROCEEDING WHICH IS AIRING LIVE
ON S.F. GOP TV'S CHANNEL 26 AS WELL AS LIVE STREAMING AT S.F.
G OF ETV BORG. YOU MAY SUBMIT YOUR PUBLIC
COMMENT IN WRITING BY SENDING AN EMAIL TO BOS AT S.F. GOV
DAWG OR USE THE POSTAL SERVICE JUST ADDRESS THE ENVELOPE TO
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON B GOODLATTE PLACE CITY HALL ROOM
244 SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA 94102 AND IF YOU NEED TO MAKE A
REASONABLE ACCOMMODATE FOR A FUTURE MEETING UNDER THE
AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT OR TO REQUEST LANGUAGE
ASSISTANCE, CONTACT THE CLERK'S OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS
DAYS IN ADVANCE BY CALLING (415) 554-5184.
THANK YOU, MEMBERS. >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> MR. PRESIDENT, YOU GOT ONE MORE THING WHICH.
YES. IN LINE WITH THE REQUEST MADE
BY SUPERVISOR FIELDER THAT SHE BE EXCUSED FROM MEETINGS UNTIL
JUNE 30TH, THE MOTION WOULD BE IN ORDER TODAY TO CONSIDER HER
REQUEST FOR TODAY'S MEETING. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
THANK YOU. CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO EXCUSE
SUPERVISOR FIELD IF FROM TODAY'S MEETING THE MOTIONS
MADE BY SUPERVISOR DORSEY AND SECONDED BY SUPERVISOR
CHEN. COLLEAGUES, I THINK WE CAN TAKE
THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION. WITHOUT OBJECTION.
SUPERVISOR FIELDER IS EXCUSED FROM TODAY'S MEETING.
>> MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO APPROVAL OF OUR MEETING
MINUTES. >> YES.
APRIL 21ST, 2026 AND APRIL 28TH 2026 BOARD MEETING MINUTES.
AND CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO APPROVE THE MINUTES AS
PRESENTED MOVED BY WALTON SECONDED BY CHERYL.
>> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS
PRESENTED? SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR FOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN I MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISORS SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
AND SUPERVISOR CHEN CHAN I THERE ARE TEN EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT
AS PRESENTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO THE CONSENT AGENDA PLEASE
CALL ITEMS ONE THROUGH SEVEN ITEMS ONE THROUGH SEVEN ARE ON
CONSENT. THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED TO
BE ROUTINE. IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY
BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY PLEASE CALL THE ROLL
ON ITEMS ONE THROUGH SEVEN SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN MANDOLIN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
AND SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN EITHER ATTORNEYS WITHOUT OBJECTION
THESE ORDINANCES ARE PASSED ON FIRST READING AND THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO UNFINISHED
BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM EIGHT ITEM EIGHT THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO ESTABLISH THE SAN
FRANCISCO HATE CRIME REWARD FUND.
>> I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER NINE ITEM NINE THIS IS
AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE BUSINESS AND TAX REGULATIONS
CODE RETROACTIVE TO JANUARY 1ST 2026 TO EXTEND FOR TEN YEARS TO
DECEMBER 31ST 2035 AN EXEMPTION FROM THE PARKING TAX
AND CERTAIN RELATED REQUIREMENTS FOR A LIMITED
NUMBER OF SPECIAL PARKING EVENTS OPERATED BY VOLUNTEER
LED NONPROFIT ORGANIZATIONS ON SCHOOL DISTRICT PROPERTY TO
BENEFIT THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC SCHOOLS AND EARNING LESS
THAN 10,000 IN RENT PER EVENT. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS TEN AND 11 TOGETHER ITEMS
TEN AND 11 ARE AN ORDINANCE AND RESOLUTION THAT PERTAIN TO
GO GENERAL OBLIGATION BOND PROCEEDS SERIES.
HEALTHY SAFE AND VIBRANT S.F. G O BONDS 2026 A.
ITEM TEN APPROPRIATES 195 MILLION OF BOND PROCEEDS TO THE
DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS
RECREATION AND PARKS DEPARTMENT AND THE MUNICIPAL
TRANSPORTATION AGENCY FOR ACQUISITION AND IMPROVEMENT OF
REAL PROPERTY FOR VARIOUS HEALTH CARE, NURSING AND MENTAL
HEALTH FACILITIES. CERTAIN TRANSPORTATION
AND PEDESTRIAN STREETS, SAFETY RELATED CAPITAL IMPROVEMENTS,
STREETSCAPE ENHANCEMENTS AND OTHER PUBLIC SPACE
IMPROVEMENTS AND RELATED COSTS IN FISCAL YEAR 20 2526 AND TO
PLACE THESE FUNDS ON CONTROLLERS RESERVE PENDING
RECEIPT OF BOND PROCEEDS. ITEM 11 THIS RESOLUTION
AUTHORIZES 195 MILLION IN THE ISSUANCE AND SALE OF A NOT TO
EXCEED AMOUNT A PRINCIPAL AMOUNT OF THE AFOREMENTIONED GO
BONDS ON A TAX EXEMPT OR TAXABLE BASIS TO PRESCRIBE THE
FORM IN TERMS OF SUCH BONDS AND ANY SUB SERIES DESIGNATION
TO PROVIDE FOR THE APPOINTMENT OF DEPOSITORIES AND OTHER
AGENTS FOR SUCH BONDS TO PROVIDE FOR THE ESTABLISHMENT
OF ACCOUNTS OR SUBACCOUNTS AND TO AUTHORIZE THE SALE OF
THE BONDS BY COMPETITIVE OR NEGOTIATED SALE OR PRIVATE
PLACEMENT AND TO APPROVE CERTAIN FORMS AND NOTICES OF
INTENTIONS AND PURCHASES OF A FORM PURCHASE OF THE CONTRACT
ITEM. >> OH, THANK YOU.
YEAH AND WE COULD TAKE THESE SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING AND THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEMS 12 AND 13 TOGETHER. >> YES, THESE ARE ITEMS 12
AND 13 ARE TWO RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE AGREEMENTS OR AGREEMENT
AMENDMENTS FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH AND THE SAN
FRANCISCO COMMUNITY HEALTH AUTHORITY ITEM 12 APPROVES THE
AGREEMENT TO PAY PRIVATE NETWORK PROVIDERS FOR THE
HEALTHY SAN FRANCISCO PROGRAM TERM OF JULY FIRST, 2026
THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2030 WITH ONE SIX YEAR OPTION TO EXTEND FOR A
TOTAL AMOUNT OF 41.6 MILLION FOR ITEM 13.
THIS APPROVES THE AGREEMENT TO PROVIDE ADMINISTRATIVE
FUNCTIONS FOR SAN FRANCISCO CITY OPTION FOR A TERM JULY 1ST
2026 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2030 WITH ONE SIX YEAR OPTION TO
EXTEND FOR A TOTAL AMOUNT OF 52.8 MILLION AND WE CAN TAKE
THESE ITEMS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK I THINK I HAVE
THIS RIGHT PLEASE CALL ITEMS 14 THROUGH SIX TOGETHER.
>> YES, MR. PRESIDENT. ITEMS 14 THROUGH 16 ARE THREE
RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE AMENDMENTS TO AGREEMENTS
BETWEEN THE PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT AND THE FOLLOWING
ENTITIES FOR ITEM 14 IT APPROVES THE FIRST AMENDMENT TO
THE AGREEMENT WITH CRESTWOOD BEHAVIORAL HEALTH INC TO
PROVIDE A CRISIS STABILIZATION UNIT AT 822 GEARY TO EXTEND THE
TERM BY TWO YEARS JUNE 30TH 2026 FOR A NEW TERM OF MARCH
1ST 2025 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2028 AND TO INCREASE THE AMOUNT BY
17.1 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL OF 26.2 MILLION ITEM 15 THIS
RESOLUTION APPROVES THE FIRST AMENDMENT TO THE AGREEMENT WITH
RICHMOND AREA MULTI SERVICES INC TO PROVIDE INTEGRATED
BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND CASE MANAGEMENT SERVICES AT 15 OF
THE HIGH SCHOOL BASED WELLNESS CENTERS TO EXTEND THE TERM BY
TWO YEARS FOR A NEW TERM OF JULY 1ST 2023 THROUGH JUNE 30TH
2028 AND TO INCREASE THE AMOUNT BY APPROXIMATELY 5.6 MILLION
FOR A NEW TOTAL AMOUNT OF 15 MILLION FOR ITEM 16.
THIS RESOLUTION APPROVES THE SECOND AMENDMENT TO THE
AGREEMENT WITH RICHMOND AREA MULTI SERVICES INC TO PROVIDE
PEER TO PEER EMPLOYMENT AND PEER SPECIALIST MENTAL
HEALTH CERTIFICATE SERVICES TO EXTEND THE TERM BY THREE YEARS
FOR A NEW TERM OF JULY 1ST 2021 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2029 AND TO
INCREASE THE AMOUNT BY 19 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL NOT TO
EXCEED AMOUNT OF 48.2 MILLION AND WE CAN TAKE THESE ITEMS
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
17 ITEM 17 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE AND AUTHORIZE THE
GENERAL MANAGER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES
COMMISSION TO EXECUTE THE FIRST AMENDMENT TO A CONTRACT FOR
ENGINEERING SERVICES FOR THE EMERGENCY FIREFIGHTING WATER
SYSTEM AND CITIES WATER DISTRIBUTION SYSTEM WITH LI
PLUS R O AND AG AS JOINT VENTURE TO INCREASE THE
CONTRACT AMOUNT BY 5 MILLION FOR A NEW CONTRACT AMOUNT OF 13
MILLION WITH NO CHANGED TO THE DURATION OF THE CONTRACT STILL
THROUGH JUNE 27TH 2032 TO PROVIDE ADDITIONAL ENGINEERING
DESIGN AND SUPPORT FOR PIPELINE IMPROVEMENT PROJECTS PURSUANT
TO CHARTER SECTION 9.118 AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS
18 AND 19 TOGETHER ITEM 18 AND 19 ARE TWO RESOLUTIONS THAT
APPROVE AMENDMENTS BETWEEN THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH
AND A CONTRACT WITH MEDLINE INDUSTRIES INC.
ITEM 18 APPROVES THE THIRD AMENDMENT TO THE AGREEMENT FOR
LOW UNIT OF MEASURE DISTRIBUTION OF MEDICAL
SURGICAL AND LABORATORY SUPPLIES TO EXTEND THE TERM BY
FOUR YEARS FOR A TOTAL TERM OF JULY 1ST 2021 THROUGH JUNE 30TH
2030 TO INCREASE THE AMOUNT BY 156.2 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL
AMOUNT OF 301 MILLION. AND TO UPDATE THE MEDLINE
MASTER DISTRIBUTION AGREEMENT AND FOR ITEM 19 THIS ITEM
APPROVES THE FOURTH AMENDMENT TO THE AGREEMENT FOR BULK
MEDICAL, SURGICAL AND LABORATORY SUPPLIES
AND SERVICES TO EXTEND THE TERM BY FOUR YEARS FOR A NEW TERM OF
JULY 1ST 2021 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2030 TO INCREASE THE AMOUNT BY
APPROXIMATELY 70.8 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL OF APPROXIMATELY
165 MILLION. AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THESE
ITEMS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ADAM 20 ITEM 20 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE
ADOPTION OF THE SAN FRANCISCO BEHAVIORAL HEALTH SERVICES ACT
THE THREE YEAR INTEGRATION PLAN FOR FISCAL YEAR 2026 THROUGH
2029 AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL ITEMS 21 AND 22 TOGETHER ITEMS 21 AND 22 ARE
TWO RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE AIRPORT LEASE TERMINATIONS FOR
ITEM 21 THIS IS FOR THE TERMINAL THREE BOARDING AREA
FOOD AND BEVERAGE CONCESSION LEASE NUMBER SIX BETWEEN GATES
74 INC AND THE CITY AND ITEM 22 IS FOR THE HARVEY MILK TERMINAL
ONE FOOD AND BEVERAGE CONCESSION LEASE IN PHASES
THREE AND FOUR LEASE 12 ARE BETWEEN H.F. AS A VOTE O LLC AS
TENANT AND THE CITY AND WILL TAKE THESE SAME HOUSE SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED MADAM
CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS 23 AND 24 TOGETHER ITEM 23 AND 24
ARE TWO RESOLUTIONS THAT RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZE THE
HUMAN SERVICES AGENCY TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND A GRANT INCREASE
IN SUPPLEMENTAL FUNDING FROM THE FEDERAL OFFICE OF REFUGEE
RESETTLEMENT PROGRAM. ITEM 23 IS ENTITLED HOUSING
ASSISTANCE FOR UKRAINIAN SAN FRANCISCO A GRANT INCREASE
IN THE AMOUNT OF 300,000 FOR A TOTAL AMOUNT OF 1.8 MILLION FOR
THE TERM THROUGH SEPTEMBER 30TH 2026 AND FOR ITEM 24 THIS IS
FOR A PROGRAM ENTITLED UKRAINIAN REFUGEE SUPPORT
SERVICES SUPPLEMENTAL FUNDING SAN FRANCISCO FOR 200,000 FOR
THE TERM OCTOBER 1ST, 2022 THROUGH SEPTEMBER 30TH 2026
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
25 THROUGH 27 TOGETHER ITEMS 25 THROUGH 27 ARE THREE
RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE CONTRACT AMENDMENTS BETWEEN THE
DEPARTMENT OF HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORT OF HOUSING AND THE
FOLLOWING TWO AGENCIES FOR ITEM 25 APPROVING THE FIRST
AMENDMENT TO THE CONTRACT WITH DISH AS IF FOR PROPERTY
MANAGEMENT SERVICES AT SIX BUILDINGS TO INCREASE THE
AGREEMENT AMOUNT BY 15.3 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL OF 25.3
MILLION TO EXTEND THE CONTRACT TERM 18 MONTHS FOR A TOTAL TERM
OF JULY 1ST 2025 THROUGH JUNE 31ST, 2027 AND FOR ITEM 26 THIS
RESOLUTION APPROVES THE FIRST AMENDMENT TO THE CONTRACT WITH
ST VINCENT DE PAUL SOCIETY OF SAN FRANCISCO FOR OPERATIONS
AND SUPPORT SERVICES AT THE DIVISION CIRCLE NAVIGATION
CENTER TO EXTEND THE TERM 36 MONTHS FOR A TOTAL TERM OF JULY
1ST 2025 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2029 AND TO INCREASE THE CONTRACT
AMOUNT BY 27.5 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL AMOUNT OF 37 MILLION
. AND FOR ITEM 27 THIS RESOLUTION
APPROVES THE CONTRACT WITH THE ST VINCENT DE PAUL SOCIETY OF
SAN FRANCISCO FOR EMERGENCY SHELTER OPERATIONS AND SUPPORT
SERVICES AT THE MULTISERVICE CENTER SOUTH FOR A TERM JULY
1ST, 2026 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2029 FOR 35 MILLION SAME HOUSE,
SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ADAMS 28 AND 29 TOGETHER ITEMS 28
AND 29 ARE TWO RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE GRANT AGREEMENT
AMENDMENTS BETWEEN THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELESSNESS
AND SUPPORTIVE HOUSING AND THE TENDERLOIN HOUSING CLINIC INC
ITEM 28 APPROVES THE SECOND AMENDMENT TO THE GRANT
AGREEMENT FOR SUPPORT OF SERVICES, PROPERTY MANAGEMENT
AND MASTER LEASING FOR THE CROWN THE WINSTON AND NATIONAL
HOTELS TO EXTEND THE TERM BY 18 MONTHS FOR A NEW TOTAL TERM
JULY 1ST 2021 THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST 2027 TO INCREASE THE
AGREEMENT AMOUNT BY 8 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL AMOUNT OF 42.5
MILLION AND FOR ITEM 29 THIS RESOLUTION APPROVES THE THIRD
AMENDMENT TO THE GRANT AGREEMENT FOR MASTER LEASE
STEWARDSHIP PROPERTY MANAGEMENT AND SUPPORT SERVICES AT 16
PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING SITES TO EXTEND THE TERM BY 18
MONTHS FOR A TOTAL TERM OF JULY 1ST 2020 THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST
2027 TO INCREASE THE AGREEMENT AMOUNT BY 61.9 MILLION FOR A
NEW TOTAL AMOUNT OF 303.6 MILLION SAME HOUSE SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 30.
ITEM 30 RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE ZONE THE DEPARTMENT OF
PUBLIC WORKS TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND A $14.5 MILLION
GRANT FROM THE SAN FRANCISCO DOWNTOWN DEVELOPMENT
CORPORATION TO FUND THE POWELL STREET IMPROVEMENT PROJECT TO
APPROVE THE ASSOCIATED GRANT AGREEMENT PURSUANT TO CHARTER
SECTION 9.118 SUB A AND TO AFFIRM THE SECOND DETERMINATION
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS
ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 31 ITEM 31 THIS RESOLUTION
APPROVES AND AUTHORIZES THE DIRECTOR OF REAL ESTATE ON
BEHALF OF MULTIPLE DEPARTMENTS TO EXECUTE A SECOND AMENDMENT
TO THE LEASE AGREEMENT WITH HUDSON 1455 MARKET STREET FOR
502,000 RENTABLE SQUARE FEET OF OFFICE SPACE AT 1455 MARKET
STREET AND WE COULD TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 32.
>> ITEM 32 WAS REFERRED WITHOUT RECOMMEND ATION FROM THE BUDGET
AND FINANCE COMMITTEE. THE RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE
SHERIFF'S OFFICE TO CONTRACT WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO PRETRIAL
DIVISION DIVERSION PROJECT PROJECT AS A PRETRIAL FOR
PRETRIAL SERVICES FOR A THREE YEAR TERM JULY 1ST 2026 THROUGH
JUNE 30TH 2029 PARDON ME FOR CONTRACT AMOUNT YET THE CLERK
22.5 MILLION WITH TWO ONE YEAR OPTIONS TO EXTEND PARDON ME.
>> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK THAT SOUNDED PAINFUL.
>> SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU. PRESIDENT MANDOLIN COLLEAGUES
THIS ITEM WAS SENT OUT FROM THE BUDGET AND FINANCE COMMITTEE
WITHOUT RECOMMENDATION AS IS OCCASIONALLY THE PRACTICE WHEN
THERE ARE SPECIAL CIRCUMSTANCES FOR WHICH COMMITTEE MEMBERS
WANT TO MAKE SURE WE APPRIZE ALL OF OUR COLLEAGUES HERE AT
THE FULL BOARD I WILL BE VOTING YES ON THIS ITEM.
HOWEVER, JUST TO EXPLAIN IT IMPLICATES A TRANSITION THAT
THE SUPERIOR COURT OF CALIFORNIA RECENTLY ANNOUNCED
TO ALIGN SAN FRANCISCO'S PRETRIAL SERVICES WITH HOW
THESE SERVICES ARE PROVIDED BY ALL OTHER CALIFORNIA COUNTIES.
IN SHORT, IT WILL DESIGNATE CIVIL SERVICE SPECIFICALLY THE
ADULT PROBATION DEPARTMENT OR APD TO PROVIDE PRETRIAL
SERVICES TO JUSTICE INVOLVED INDIVIDUALS.
IT WOULD ULTIMATELY REPLACE THE NONPROFIT PARTNER NAMED IN THIS
CONTRACT THE SAN FRANCISCO PRETRIAL DIVERSION PROJECT
WHICH IS HISTORICALLY HAND IF THESE SERVICES AS I BELIEVE
MOST OF OUR OFFICERS WERE INFORMED BY THE PRESIDING JUDGE
THE SUPERIOR COURT HAS EXPRESSED CONCERNS ABOUT
PRETRIAL FINANCIAL STABILITY, TRANSPARENCY MANAGEMENT
AND ACCURACY OF PROGRESS REPORTS FOR THOSE UNDER
PRETRIAL SUPERVISION. AT THE COMMITTEE WE DISCUSSED
THE THREE YEAR LENGTH OF THIS CONTRACT AS POTENTIALLY
PROBLEMATIC GIVEN THIS TRANSITION, GIVEN THAT WE CAN'T
AMEND CONTRACTS IN COMMITTEE, WE DISCUSSED HOW FUNDING FOR
THIS CONTRACT WOULD OCCUR VIS A VIS THE SHERIFF'S BUDGET
AND HOW THE MAYOR'S OFFICE PLANS TO FUND APD.
WE ARRIVED AT AN AGREED UPON CONCLUSION WIDELY OFFERED BY
OUR BUDGET CHAIR CONNIE CHEN THAT WE SHOULD EXPRESS OUR
INTENT TO FUND THE CONTRACT FOR ONE YEAR AND PUT TWO YEARS OF
THE FUNDING ON THIS CONTRACT FOR YEARS ON RESERVE THAT WILL
ALLOW MORE TIME AND FLEXIBILITY AND ALSO ENABLE US TO HAVE MORE
PLANNING TO TAKE PLACE REGARDING WHAT'S NEEDED TO COST
EFFECTIVELY MIGRATE THE NONPROFIT SERVICES PROVIDED BY
US OF PRETRIAL TO CIVIL SERVICE UNDER A PD'S DIRECTION.
I'M INFORMED BY OUR CITY ATTORNEY THAT NOTWITHSTANDING
THE THREE YEAR TERM REFERENCED IN THIS ITEM THE CONTRACT DOES
ALLOW FOR A TERMINATION IN THE EVENT OF NON APPROPRIATION
MEANING WE CAN TERMINATE THE PRETRIAL CONTRACT WITHOUT
PENALTY LIABILITY OR EXPENSE OF ANY KIND TO THE CITY.
IF I UNDERSTAND THAT CORRECTLY I AM RELATEDLY INFORMED BY APD
THAT THEY ARE NOT READY TO START ON JULY 1ST ANYWAY SO
THIS SHARED UNDERSTAND TING WILL HELP US MAKE SURE THAT WE
FACILITATE THIS WELL I HOPE THIS EXPLAINS WHY THIS WAS SENT
WITHOUT RECOMMENDATION AND I HOPE THIS APPROACH WILL HAVE
YOUR SUPPORT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY SEEING NOBODY ELSE IN THE QUEUE WELL LET'S
TAKE THIS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS
33 THROUGH 36 TOGETHER ITEMS 33 THROUGH 36 OR FOR ORDINANCES
REGARDING PUBLIC UTILITY COMMISSION REVENUE BONDS IN A
AN APPROPRIATION ITEM 33 APPROPRIATES ALL ESTIMATED
CAPITAL PROJECT RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURE EXPENDITURES
FOR THE PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION FOR THE FISCAL YEAR
ENDING JUNE 30TH 2027 AND JUNE 30TH 2028 AND 34 AUTHORIZES
ISSUANCE AND SALE OF TAX EXEMPT OR TAXABLE POWER REVENUE BONDS
AND OTHER FORMS OF DEBT BY THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES
COMMISSION FOR 1.100 38.1 MILLION TO FINANCE A COURSE OF
VARIOUS CAPITAL PROJECTS BENEFITING THE POWER ENTERPRISE
PURSUANT TO AMENDMENTS TO THE CHARTER OF THE CITY ENACTED BY
THE VOTERS AS PROPOSITION A TO AUTHORIZE ISSUANCE OF POWER
REVENUE REFUNDING BONDS AND THE RETIREMENT OF OUTSTANDING
PUBLIC POWER ENTERPRISE COMMERCIAL PAPER TO DECLARE THE
OFFICIAL INTENT OF THE COMMISSION TO REIMBURSE ITSELF
WITH ONE OR MORE ISSUES OF TAX EXEMPT OR TAXABLE BONDS OR
OTHER FORMS OF DEBT AND 35 AUTHORIZES THE ISSUANCE
AND SALE OF TAX EXEMPT OR TAXABLE WASTEWATER REVENUE
BONDS AND OTHER FORMS OF DEBT BY THE PUC FOR 1.1 BILLION OH
AND 30 AND 36 AND 36 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AUTHORIZE THE
ISSUANCE AND SALE OF TAX EXEMPT OR TAXABLE WATER REVENUE BONDS
AND OTHER FORMS OF INDEBTEDNESS BY THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC
UTILITIES COMMISSION AND AGGREGATE PRINCIPAL AMOUNT
NOT TO EXCEED APPROXIMATELY 570 MILLION.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. LET'S TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
ARE PASSED ON FIRST READING AND PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 37.
>> ITEM NUMBER 37 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE BUILDING
CODE TO ADJUST FEES CHARGED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING
INSPECTION AMENDING THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO ALLOW
THE DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING INSPECTION AND PLANNING
DEPARTMENT TO CHARGE NOTARY FEES AND AFFIRMED SECOND
DETERMINATION SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS 38 AND 39 TOGETHER ITEMS
38 AND 39 OR 2 RESOLUTIONS REGARDING PROP J CERTIFICATIONS
. ITEM 38 IS THE RESOLUTION TO
CONCUR WITH THE COMPTROLLER CERTIFICATION THAT DEPARTMENT
SERVICES CAN BE PERFORMED BY PRIVATE CONTRACTOR FOR A LOW
COST AND SIMILAR WORK PERFORMED BY CITY AND COUNTY EMPLOYEES
FOR PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR THE PUC AND ITEM 39 IS A RESOLUTION
TO CONCUR WITH THE COMPTROLLER CERTIFICATION THAT DEPARTMENT
SERVICES PREVIOUSLY APPROVED CAN BE PERFORMED BY PRIVATE
CONTRACTOR OR FOR A LOWER COST AND SIMILAR WORK PERFORMED BY
CITY EMPLOYEES FOR THE FOLLOWING SERVICES SECURITY
INFORMATION AND GUEST SERVICES PARKING OPERATIONS SHUTTLE BUS
SERVICES AT THE AIRPORT CITATIONS PARATRANSIT PARKING
METER COLLECTIONS SECURITY TOWING TRANSIT SHELTER CLEANING
SERVICES AT MTA JANITORIAL SERVICES AT THE PORT
AND SECURITY SERVICES AT P.S. AND WE CAN TAKE THESE ITEMS
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED. >> PLEASE CALL ITEM 40.
ITEM NUMBER 40 IS A RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE PUBLIC LIBRARY
TO ACCEPTING AND EXPEND APPROXIMATELY 1.1 MILLION GRANT
OF IN-KIND GIFTS, SERVICES AND CASH MONEYS FROM THE
FRIENDS OF THE PUBLIC LIBRARY FOR DIRECT SUPPORT FOR A
VARIETY OF PUBLIC PROGRAMS AND SERVICES IN FISCAL YEAR 20
2627. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED PLEASE CALL
ITEM 41 ITEM 41 IS AN ORDINANCE TO APPROVE AMENDED SURVEILLANCE
TECHNOLOGY POLICIES FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS USE
OF UNMANNED AERIAL VEHICLES AND THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC
WORKS USE OF AN ILLEGAL DUMPING CAMERA SYSTEM WITH AUTOMATIC
LICENSE PLATE READER TECHNOLOGY AND CAMERAS AND MAKING REQUIRED
FINDINGS IN SUPPORT OF SAID APPROVALS.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
IS PASSED ON FIRST READING PLEASE CALL ITEM 42.
ITEM NUMBER 42 IS A RESOLUTION TO SUPPORT CALIFORNIA STATE
ASSEMBLY BILL 1837 WHICH WILL AUTHORIZE THE USE OF VIDEO
IMAGING TO ENFORCE PARKING AND STOPPING VIOLATIONS
IN TRANSIT ONLY LANES AND BIKEWAYS INDEFINITELY.
>> A SUPER ADVISOR WHAT CAN WE DO?
>> A ROLL CALL PLEASE FOR MY CLERK PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
ITEM 42 AND ITEM 42. >> SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MAHMUD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SARDAR SARDAR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON CO SUPERVISOR WANG WANG
I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN EITHER NINE EYES AND ONE NO WAS SUPERB
SUPERVISOR WALTON VOTING NO AND THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED
AND MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 43.
>> ITEM NUMBER 43 IS A RESOLUTION TO RECOGNIZE APRIL
6TH, 2026 AS THE 100TH ANNIVERSARY OF UNITED AIRLINES
AND ITS CENTRAL ROLE IN SAN FRANCISCO'S ECONOMY AND GLOBAL
CONNECTIVITY. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM
43 SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMUD MAHMUD I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN HI
AMENDMENT I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN EITHER TEN
EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED MADAM
CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR 2:30 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER OR TWO SPECIAL
ORDER AT 230 IS A RECOGNITION ACCOMMODATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS
SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> WE START TODAY WITH DISTRICT ONE SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU
PRESIDENT AMENDMENT COLLEAGUES I WOULD LIKE TO WELCOME
RICHMOND STATION CAPTAIN KEVIN LEE AND OFFICER JIMMY TRAN
WHERE SO FORTUNATE TO HAVE THEIR GREAT PRESENCE IN THE
RICHMOND AND THEIR DEDICATIONS TO PUBLIC SAFETY.
CAPTAIN KEVIN LEE IS A 26 YEAR OLD ONE NOT 26 YEAR OLD 26
YEARS. HE LOOKS LIKE A 26 YEAR OLD.
MY APOLOGIES. CAPTAIN LEE IS A 26 YEAR
LINEMAN. FORESMAN VETERAN SERVING 19
YEARS WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT AND SEVEN
YEARS WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT.
THROUGHOUT HIS CAREER HE HAS WORKED AT SEVEN OF THE CITY'S
TEN DISTRICT STATIONS. CAPTAIN LEE STRONGLY BELIEVE
THAT PATROL IS THE BACKBONE OF EVERY POLICE DEPARTMENT
AND EVERY DISTRICT AND EVERY NEIGHBORHOOD ESPECIALLY AS A
BILINGUAL CANTONESE SPEAKER, HE RECOGNIZES THE IMPORTANCE OF
LANGUAGE, ACCESS AND CULTURAL COMPETENCY AND UNDERSTANDING
IN THE MODERN POLICING IN SAN FRANCISCO BY BRIDGING
COMMUNICATION GAPS HE STRIVES TO STRENGTHEN RELATIONSHIPS
IN NEIGHBORHOODS THAT HAVE HISTORICALLY FELT UNDERSERVED.
SO THANK YOU, CAPTAIN LEE FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND BUILDING
SUCH A GREAT TEAM BRINGING IN OFFICER LIKE OFFICER JIMMY
TRENT TO SERVE THIS COMMUNITY. AND SO FOR OFFICER JIMMY TRAN
AND THE START IS 168. >> THAT'S A GOOD NUMBER.
THAT'S A GREAT NUMBER IS A TRUE SON OF SAN FRANCISCO BORN
AND RAISED IN THE RICHMOND DISTRICT, HE ATTENDED ALAMO
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, PRESIDIO MIDDLE AND WASHINGTON HIGH
SCHOOL BEFORE EARNING BOTH HIS BACHELOR AND MASTER'S DEGREES
FROM SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY OFFICER TREND BEGAN
HIS FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT CAREER IN 2014 AFTER GRADUATING
FOR THE POLICE ACADEMY, HE BEGAN FIELD TRAINING AT
INGLESIDE STATION WITH SUBSEQUENT ASSIGNMENTS AT
CENTRAL AND BAYVIEW STATION FOLLOWED BY THE PROFESSIONAL
STANDARD UNITS TODAY HE PROUDLY SERVES THE NEIGHBORHOOD THAT
RAISED HIM AT THE ASTI COMMANDS CLEMENT STREET BEAT OFFICER
AND RICHMOND STATION OFFICER TRENT IS TRILINGUAL FLUENT
IN ENGLISH, CANTONESE AND CHUCHO OFTEN SEEN ENGAGING
AND CONVERSING WITH RESIDENTS AND MERCHANTS ON THE CORRIDORS
AND I KNOW THIS TO BE TRUE BECAUSE WHEN I VISIT THE
CORRIDORS WHENEVER I BUMP INTO HIM AND WHENEVER ALONG WITH
OTHER MERCHANTS THEY LOVE HIM THEY REALLY DO AND JUST
RESIDENT JUST LOVE OFFICER TRAN AND JUST RECOGNIZE HIM
EVERYWHERE HE GOES AND THAT IS THE KIND OF OFFICER WE NEED.
I WANT TO HIGHLIGHT REASON RECENT INCIDENTS THAT REALLY
EXEMPLIFY OFFICER TRENDS OUTSTANDING SERVICE
PROFESSIONAL ISM AND KINDNESS. OFFICER TRAN SAW A SENIOR
WAITING AT THE BUS SHOUTER THAT IS NOT IN SERVICE.
HE IMMEDIATELY RECOGNIZED HIM AS SOMEONE WHO FREQUENT CLEMENT
STREET AND WAS NOT ABLE TO GO HOME BY HIMSELF.
OFFICER TRAN CALLED FOR APPROVAL, GAVE THE GENTLEMAN
THE RIDE HOME AND CONNECTED WITH THE FAMILY WITH
INFORMATION ABOUT SPEEDY'S MEDICAL BRACELET TO HELP FIRST
RESPONDERS IN CASE OF FUTURE EMERGENCY.
>> SO THANK YOU. THANK YOU, CAPTAIN LEE.
THANK YOU OFFICER TRAN FOR GOING ABOVE AND BEYOND IN YOUR
SERVICE TO THE RICHMOND STATION AND SAN FRANCISCO AND I BELIEVE
THAT CAPTAIN LEE HAVE A FEW REMARKS FIRST BUT I ALSO SEE I
SEE IN IN OUR NEIGHBORING DISTRICT SUPERVISOR STEVE
AND CHERYL ALSO HAVE REMARKS. BUT JUST THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
BEING HERE. WE'RE SO GRATEFUL TO YOU
SUPERVISOR CHAN FIRST OF ALL, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR HONORING
THESE TWO HEROES. >> I AM VERY LUCKY EVEN THOUGH
WE'RE JUST ON THE OTHER SIDE OF ARGUELLO I'M VERY LUCKY TO
BENEFIT FROM RICHMOND STATION CAPTAIN LEE YOUR LEADERSHIP
AND THANK YOU FOR BEING SUCH STEWARDS OF OUR COMMUNITY
AND FOR LEADING YOUR COMMUNITY FIRST YOUR COMPASSION AND YOUR
EMPATHETIC AND YOU SEE THE PEOPLE WHO LIVE AND WORK IN THE
DISTRICT IN THE RICHMOND EVERY DAY.
SO THANK YOU VERY MUCH AND SUPERVISOR CHAN, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH FOR HONORING THESE TWO HEROES.
THANK YOU. GOOD AFTERNOON.
YOUR SUPERVISOR, CHANTE SUPERVISOR CHERYL PRESIDENT
RANDLEMAN AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS COMMANDER
AMY HOROWITZ REPRESENTING THE POLICE DEPARTMENT AND MEMBERS
OF THE COMMUNITY. THANK YOU FOR YOUR OPPORTUNITY
TO BE HERE TODAY AND FOR RECOGNIZING OFFICER JIMMIE TRAN
WITH THIS SPECIAL COMMENDATION .
I WOULD FIRST LIKE TO THANK SUPERVISOR CONNIE CHAN FOR HER
CONTINUED PARTNERSHIP AND UNWAVERING SUPPORT OF
PUBLIC SAFETY. OUR NEIGHBORHOODS AND THE MEN
AND WOMEN OF THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT.
>> WE ARE ALSO GRATEFUL TO THE ENTIRE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS FOR
YOUR LEADERSHIP AND SUPPORT OF OUR CITY EMPLOYEES WHO SERVE
THE PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO EVERY DAY.
IT IS TRULY AN HONOR TO RECOGNIZE OFFICER JIMMIE TRAN.
JIMMIE REPRESENTS THE VERY BEST OF SAN FRANCISCO.
HE WAS BORN AND RAISED IN THE RICHMOND DISTRICT, ATTENDED
LOCAL PUBLIC SCHOOLS AND CHOSE TO DEDICATE HIS LIFE TO SERVING
THE SAME COMMUNITY THAT HELPED SHAPE WHO HE IS TODAY.
>> OFFICER TRAN IS NOT ONLY AN OUTSTANDING POLICE OFFICER BUT
ALSO A COMPASSIONATE AND PROFESSIONAL PUBLIC SERVANT
WHETHER HE IS WALKING THE CLEMENT STREET FLIPPY HELPING
RESIDENTS AND MERCHANTS OR BUILDING TRUST WITH OUR
COMMUNITY MEMBERS, JIMMY CONSISTENTLY GOES ABOVE
AND BEYOND THE CALL OF DUTY AS A HUSBAND FATHER AND PROUD SON
OF SAN FRANCISCO OFFICER TRAN EXEMPLIFIES THE VALUES WE
STRIVE FOR IN POLICING SERVICE, INTEGRITY, EMPATHY
AND COMMUNITY PARTNERSHIP. ON BEHALF OF RICHMOND STATION
AND THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT, I AM PROUD TO STAND
BESIDE OFFICER JIMMY TRAN TODAY .
CONGRATULATIONS JIMMY AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR DEDICATION
AND SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
THANK YOU PRESIDENT OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, COMMANDER HURWITZ,
CITY HALL STAFF AND MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC.
I'M GRATEFUL AND HONOR AND APPRECIATIVE TO BE HERE
TODAY. TO BE HONEST, I CAME HERE WITH
A LITTLE HESITATION. IN LIGHT OF RECENT EVENTS TWO
NIGHTS AGO ONE OF OUR OFFICERS WERE INJURED IN THE LINE OF
DUTY AND I WAS ON THAT CALL AND WHAT I SAW THAT NIGHT WAS A
DEPARTMENT THAT CAME TOGETHER SEAMLESSLY WHEN IT MATTERED
MOST OFFICERS RAN TOWARDS DANGER AND DID SO WITHOUT ANY
HESITATION. THEY DID THE JOB.
THE FACT THAT I WAS BROUGHT HERE TODAY WAS ABOUT TAKING A
MOMENT TO HELP AN ELDERLY PERSON OUT IN THE RICHMOND
DISTRICT THAT TOO IS ALSO A JOB ASIDE FROM RUNNING TOWARDS
DANGER, TAKING THE TIME AND SLOWING DOWN FOR THE PERSON
IN FRONT OF YOU IS ALSO IMPORTANT ROLE.
BEFORE I GO ANY FURTHER I'D LIKE TO THANK MY WIFE WHO HOLDS
SUPPORT AT HOME SO THAT I CAN FOCUS ON THE JOB AT HAND
AND WITHOUT HER LOVE, SUPPORT AND SACRIFICE I CANNOT FOCUS ON
MY DAILY JOB. TO MY COLLEAGUES AT RICHMOND
STATION AND ACROSS THE DEPARTMENT.
YOU'RE ALSO A BIG REASON WHY I SHOW UP TO WORK EVERY DAY.
YOU KEEP ON COMING DESPITE HAVING HARD DAYS, SOME MORE
TAXING THAN OTHERS BUT YOU KEEP ON SHOWING UP AND THAT TO ME IS
THE HONOR BEHIND WEARING THIS UNIFORM.
TODAY I AM ACCEPTING THIS AWARD NOT FOR MYSELF BUT FOR MY WIFE
WHO SUPPORTS ME DAY IN, DAY OUT FOR THE RICHMOND DISTRICT, THE
COMMUNITY THAT PLAYED A ROLE IN RAISING ME AND SHAPING ME TO
BE WHO I AM TODAY AND THAT I'M PROUD TO SERVE FOR MY
COLLEAGUES AT RICHMOND STATION WHO PROVIDES A POSITIVE WORKING
ENVIRONMENT FOR ME TO GO TO WORK EVERY DAY FOR THE OFFICER
FIGHTING TO HAVE A FULL RECOVERY A RECOVERY AT THE
HOSPITAL BED RIGHT NOW AS WE'RE SPEAKING AND FOR EVERYONE ELSE
WHO'S GOING TO BE PUTTING BACK ON THIS UNIFORM TOMORROW JUST
TO DO THIS JOB ALL OVER AGAIN. >> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THIS MOMENT BELONGS TO EVERYONE
. >> DISTRICT FOUR SUPERVISOR
WANG. >> GOOD AFTERNOON, COLLEAGUES.
TODAY I'M HONORED TO RECOGNIZE TARIQ CASTRO RECOGNIZING HER
FOR HER OUTSTANDING DEDICATION ,LEADERSHIP AND SERVICE TO THE
STUDENTS, FAMILIES AND STAFF OF A.P. GIANNINI MIDDLE SCHOOL
IN THE OUTER SUNSET WHERE MY YOUNGER BROTHER ALAN.
>> BEFORE I BEGIN, I ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE PRINCIPAL'S
EDUCATORS AND SCHOOL LEADERS WHO ARE HERE WITH US TODAY.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE AND FOR THE IMPORTANT WORK YOU
DO EVERY DAY TO SUPPORT OUR STUDENTS, TEACHERS AND SCHOOL
COMMUNITIES. YOUR PRESENCE HERE SPEAKS
VOLUMES ABOUT THE RESPECT AND ADMIRATION THAT TARA HAS
EARNED THROUGHOUT HER CAREER. >> TARA HAS BEEN TEACHING
MIDDLE SCHOOL SINCE 2011 AND HAS BEEN A CORNERSTONE OF
THE GIANNINI COMMUNITY SINCE 2012.
OVER THE YEARS SHE HAS TAUGHT SOCIAL STUDIES AND ENGLISH
LANGUAGE ARTS ACROSS MULTIPLE GRADE LEVELS HELPING STUDENTS
DEVELOP NOT ONLY ACADEMIC SKILLS BUT ALSO CONFIDENCE
CURIOSITY AND A LOVE OF LEARNING.
>> IN ADDITION TO HER WORK IN THE CLASSROOM, TARA HAS
SERVED AS A TEACHER LEADER IN THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE ARTS
DEPARTMENT AND INSTRUCTIONAL COACH AND A MENTOR TO FELLOW
EDUCATORS. SHE HAS ALSO ENRICHED STUDENT
LIFE BY LEADING A WRITING CLUB AND A BOOK CLUB CREATING
OPPORTUNITIES FOR STUDENTS TO EXPLORE THEIR INTERESTS
AND BUILD MEANINGFUL CONNECTIONS.
>> WHAT MAKES HER TRULY EXCEPTIONAL IS THE CARE
AUTHENTICITY AND PASSION SHE BRINGS TO HER WORK EACH DAY.
SHE CREATES A LEARNING ENVIRONMENT WHERE STUDENTS FEEL
SUPPORTED, CHALLENGED AND EMPOWERED TO SUCCEED.
HER ABILITY TO BUILD STRONG RELATIONSHIPS WITH STUDENTS
AND FAMILIES HAS MADE A LASTING IMPACT ON COUNTLESS YOUNG
PEOPLE. AND HER COLLEAGUES CONSISTENTLY
DESCRIBE HER AS A TRUSTED LEADER, COLLABORATOR AND SOURCE
OF SUPPORT BEYOND ACADEMICS, TARA HELPS FOSTER A SCHOOL
CULTURE ROOTED IN RESPECT, BELONGING AND HIGH
EXPECTATIONS. SHE EMBODIES THE VERY BEST OF
PUBLIC EDUCATION AND REPRESENTS THE PROFOUND DIFFERENCE THAT
DEDICATED TEACHERS MAKE IN THE LIVES OF THEIR STUDENTS AND IN
OUR COMMUNITIES. TARA ON BEHALF OF THE RESIDENTS
OF DISTRICT FOUR AND THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO,
THANK YOU FOR YOUR YEARS OF SERVICE, YOUR COMMITMENT TO OUR
YOUNG PEOPLE AND YOUR COUNTLESS CONTRIBUTIONS TO APD.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH TO SUPERVISOR WONG AND THE BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS FOR THIS HONOR. THANK YOU ALSO TO DR. CHRISTINA
ZHANG WHO IS HERE WITH ME FOR NOMINATING ME FOR THIS
COMMENDATION AND FOR BEING HERE TODAY.
I ALSO HAVE MY HUSBAND COLIN AND A FORMER STUDENT MAX
AND HIS MOM STACY WHO ALSO WORKS AT OUR SCHOOL.
SO THANK YOU TO THEM. THIS MEANS SO MUCH TO ME.
IT GIVES ME THE CHANCE TO REFLECT ON AND COMMUNICATE HOW
GRATEFUL I AM FOR MY STUDENTS, MY COLLEAGUES AND THIS CAREER.
I REALLY ENJOY GOING TO WORK EVERY DAY TO TEACH THE YOUNG
PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO SOME OF MY SIXTH GRADERS LITERALLY RUN
INTO THE CLASSROOM ASKING WHAT ARE WE DOING TODAY?
I DO GET IRRITATED BY THIS SOMETIMES BECAUSE I HEAR THAT
QUESTION PROBABLY TEN TIMES PER DAY.
AND BY JUNE EACH YEAR MY PATIENCE IS HELD TOGETHER WITH
A PAPER CLIP AND SOME SCOTCH TAPE.
>> BUT WHEN I LOOK CLOSER AT THE SIXTH GRADER ASKING WHAT
ARE WE DOING TODAY? I CAN SEE THAT IT COMES FROM A
PLACE OF EAGERNESS, CURIOSITY AND JOY.
>> SIXTH GRADERS SOMETIMES ACT LIKE TEENS BUT THEY STILL SKIP
DOWN THE HALLWAYS WHEN THEY'RE HAVING A GOOD DAY AND GIVE
DAISY CHAIN NECKLACES AND COOL ROCKS THEY FOUND TO THEIR
TEACHERS. >> AS THE STUDENTS GET OLDER
IN SEVENTH AND EIGHTH GRADE THEIR JOY LOOKS A LITTLE LESS
OBVIOUS. BUT I'VE LEARNED IT'S STILL
THERE. IT'S THE SMILEY FACE DRAWN IN A
CORNER OF THE WHITEBOARD ON THEIR WAY OUT OF THE ROOM OR A
KID WHO WANTS TO READ WHAT HE WROTE OUT LOUD TO ME BEFORE
TURNING IT IN. IT WARMS MY ENGLISH TEACHERS
HEART WHEN I HEAR MY TEENAGE STUDENTS SAY THINGS LIKE THIS
BOOK WAS REALLY GOOD OR CAN YOU READ MY CONCLUSION OR IS THIS
HOW YOU USE A SEMICOLON? >> NICE.
SOME OF THEM ARE TALLER THAN I AM BUT THEY'RE STILL KIDS
INSIDE AND THEY THRIVE WITH GUIDANCE, ENCOURAGEMENT
AND SUPPORT FOR THE ADULTS AT A MIDDLE SCHOOL.
>> PROVIDING THE KIND OF SUPPORT AND GUIDANCE THAT TEENS
NEED WILL REALLY DO A NUMBER ON YOUR NERVOUS SYSTEM.
I FEEL SO GRATEFUL FOR MY COLLEAGUES AT AP GIANNINI
MIDDLE SCHOOL WHO PROVIDE THAT SUPPORT EVERY DAY TO STUDENTS.
THEY LISTEN DEEPLY AND SERIOUSLY TO THEIR STUDENTS
THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL DAY EVEN IF IT'S ABOUT SOMETHING ADULTS
MIGHT CLASSIFY AS SILLY BUT IS BRINGING A STUDENT TO TEARS.
I'M ALSO INSPIRED BY HOW ENCOURAGING MY FELLOW TEACHERS
ARE TO OUR STUDENTS REMINDING THEM OF THINGS WE ALL NEED TO
HEAR LIKE IT'S OKAY TO TRY DIFFICULT THINGS AND MAKE
MISTAKES. THE PATIENCE THEY HAVE IS
INCREDIBLE AND I'M SO GRATEFUL TO DO THIS WORK ALONGSIDE THEM.
>> THE MOMENTS OF HUMAN CONNECTION AT A MIDDLE SCHOOL
ARE CONSTANT AND CAN GIVE YOU EMOTIONAL WHIPLASH WITHIN A TWO
MINUTE TIME SPAN. >> YOU MIGHT HAVE INTERACTIONS
THAT ARE FRUSTRATING THEN SAD THEN HILARIOUS.
I'M SO GRATEFUL TO RIDE THIS MIDDLE SCHOOL ROLLER COASTER
IN THE SUNSET DISTRICT OF SAN FRANCISCO AND GRATEFUL THAT I
GET TO CONNECT WITH THE JOY OF OUR SAN FRANCISCO YOUTH AND BE
WITH THEM ON THEIR JOURNEY OF GROWING UP.
>> LET'S CONTINUE TO WORK TOGETHER AS A CITY TO SUPPORT
THE VITAL WORK OF PUBLIC EDUCATION AND HONOR THE WORK
BEING DONE IN SCHOOLS LIKE YOU'RE DOING HERE TODAY.
>> THANK YOU
. >> DISTRICT TEN SUPERVISOR
WALTON THANK YOU PRESIDENT MADAM AND COLLEAGUES TODAY I
RISE TO CELEBRATE AN EXTRAORDINARY PUBLIC SERVANT, A
RESPECTED LEADER AND A DEDICATED MEMBER OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO FAMILY. >> DARRYL ROBINSON FOR.
>> FOR MORE THAN THREE DECADES DARROW HAS DEVOTED HIS CAREER
TO SERVING THE PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO THROUGH THE SAN
FRANCISCO MUNICIPAL TRANSPORTATION AGENCY.
BEGINNING HIS JOURNEY IN 1989, HE ROSE THROUGH THE RANKS
THROUGH HARD WORK, EXPERTISE AND UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO
EXCELLENCE. AND ALONG THE WAY HE HELPED
MODERNIZE CRITICAL TRANSPORTATION INFRASTRUCTURE,
SUPPORTING INNOVATIVE TECHNOLOGY PROJECTS, STRENGTHEN
OPERATIONS AND ENSURE THAT THE SYSTEMS OUR CITY RELY UPON
EVERY DAY CONTINUE TO SERVE RESIDENTS EFFICIENTLY
AND EFFECTIVELY. BUT DARRELL'S LEGACY EXTENDS
FAR BEYOND PROJECTS, PROGRAMS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS.
THOSE WHO HAVE WORKED ALONGSIDE HIM KNOW HIM AS A MENTOR, A
PROBLEM SOLVER AND A LEADER WHO BELIEVED IN CREATING
OPPORTUNITIES FOR OTHERS. HE FOSTERED A CULTURE OF
INCLUSION, CHAMPIONED FAIRNESS AND EQUITY AND INVESTED
IN GROWTH AND SUCCESS OF THE PEOPLE AROUND HIM.
>> HIS LEADERSHIP HELPED SHAPE NOT ONLY THE WORK OF THE AGENCY
BUT ALSO THE CAREERS OF COUNTLESS COLLEAGUES WHO
BENEFITED FROM HIS GUIDANCE AND SUPPORT.
THROUGH HIS DEDICATION, PROFESSIONALISM AND INTEGRITY,
DARROW HAS HELPED MAKE SAN FRANCISCO A BETTER PLACE FOR
RESIDENTS, WORKERS AND VISITORS ALIKE.
>> I WANT TO EXTEND MY DEEPEST GRATITUDE FOR YOUR YEARS OF
FAITHFUL SERVICE TO THIS CITY. YOUR CONTRIBUTIONS HAVE LEFT A
LASTING MARK HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO AND YOUR LEADERSHIP
WILL CONTINUE TO INSPIRE THOSE WHO FOLLOW IN YOUR FOOTSTEPS.
AS YOU BEGIN THIS WELL EARNED RETIREMENT, WE CELEBRATE NOT
ONLY A REMARKABLE CAREER BUT ALSO THE COUNTLESS LIVES YOU'VE
TOUCHED ALONG THE WAY. CONGRATULATIONS, DARRELL
AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR EXTRAORDINARY SERVICE TO SAN
FRANCISCO. AND DARRELL, BEFORE YOU SPEAK,
I BELIEVE WE HAVE YOUR SUPERVISOR VICTORIA WISE WHO IS
HERE TO SAY A FEW WORDS ON BEHALF OF DIRECTOR KIRSCHBAUM
WHO COULDN'T BE HERE OF COURSE, BECAUSE SHE IS IN HER OWN MTA
BOARD OF DIRECTORS MEETING. >> INDEED.
PRESIDENT NEEDLEMAN MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
THANK YOU FOR THIS OPPORTUNITY TO ACKNOWLEDGE THIS INCREDIBLE
PERSON DARRELL WHO HAS DONE SO MUCH FOR S.F. MTA BUT ALSO FOR
THE CITY AS A WHOLE. I MET DARRELL WHEN HE WAS
MANAGING OUR METER SHOP WHICH BY THE WAY IS NO SMALL JOB.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT A BUDGET OF $20 MILLION AND WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT MAINTAINING AND OPERATING 26,000M IN THE CITY OF SAN
FRANCISCO. AND HE DID AN EXEMPLARY JOB
IN THAT WHICH IS WHY HE WAS PROMOTED TO RUN THE ENTIRE
OPERATIONS OF THE CITY AND WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THE
SIGN SHOP. WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THE PAINT
SHOP AND THE TEMPORARY SIGN SHOP FOR SPECIAL EVENTS ALL THE
THINGS ALL THE BREAD AND BUTTER THINGS THAT MTA DOES TO MAKE
OUR CITY RUN. THE PERSON BEHIND THAT IS
DARRELL. AND HE HAS BEEN OUTSTANDING NOT
IN JUST EXECUTING THE DAY TO DAY WORK THAT WE DO BUT OF
GROWING A LEADERSHIP TEAM BEHIND HIM.
HE IS LEAVING BEHIND INCREDIBLE LEADERS IN THAT ORGANIZATION
AND A REALLY, REALLY STRONG TEAM FOR WHICH I AM PERSONALLY
GRATEFUL FOR DARRELL AND THAT'S AN INCREDIBLE LEGACY THAT YOU
ARE LEAVING US WITH THE CITY AND S.F. MTA IN PARTICULAR.
>> I ALSO WANT TO TELL YOU GUYS HE'S EXEMPLARY PUBLIC SERVICE
EMPLOYEE BECAUSE HE WHEN I CALL HIM TO SOLVE PROBLEMS THE
ANSWER IS ALWAYS LET ME SEE HOW I CAN FIGURE IT OUT.
LET ME SEE HOW I CAN NAVIGATE CERTAIN UNIQUE SITUATIONS OR
HOW CAN I MAKE SOMETHING WORK? THE ANSWER FOR DARRELL IS
ALWAYS YES AND THAT EXEMPLIFIES THE VERY KIND OF PUBLIC
SERVANTS THAT WE WANT TO BE AND WHY I'M SO PROUD TO HAVE
HIM AS A COLLEAGUE. >> THE OTHER THING THAT I WOULD
TELL YOU ABOUT DARRELL, HE IS A TEAM PLAYER WITH A CAPITAL T.
DARRELL HAS TOLD ME MANY, MANY TIMES TEAMWORK IS WHAT MAKES
THE DREAM WORK AND THAT HAS BECOME THE MOTTO OF THE STREETS
DIVISION OF S.F. MTA AND WE USE THAT EVERY SINGLE DAY AND THAT
IS HOW WE OPERATE AND THAT IS HOW WE SERVE THE CITY TODAY.
>> SO WITH THAT I JUST WANT TO TELL YOU THAT DARRELL IS THE
HEART AND SOUL OF MY DIVISION AND I'M GOING TO BE VERY SAD TO
SEE HIM GO BUT HONESTLY ALSO VERY EXCITED FOR YOU TO SPEND
MORE TIME WITH YOUR FAMILY. IT'S BEEN AN HONOR SERVING WITH
YOU, DARRELL. TRULY.
>> THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR PRESIDENT AS WELL AS SUPERVISOR WALTON AND ALL THE
SUPERVISORS. IT'S BEEN AN HONOR
AND PRIVILEGE TO SERVE THE CITIZENS OF SAN FRANCISCO BUT I
WANTED TO TELL THEM A LITTLE BIT HISTORY IS HOW I ARRIVED TO
SERVING THIS TO BECOMING THE PERSON I BECAME.
AS A YOUNG KID GROWING UP IN THE BABY BOOMERS POINT.
I WAS I'M THE PRODUCT OF THE FIRST GENERATION OF KIDS THAT
WERE BUSED AROUND THE SCHOOLS IN SAN FRANCISCO AND AS A
RESULT OF THAT WHEN OCTOBER IN 1974 A COUPLE OF MY
COLLEAGUES WENT TO THE SWIMMING POOL AT MARTIN LUTHER KING
SWIMMING POOL AND THEY ACTUALLY DROWNED AS A RESULT OF THAT.
MY PARENTS AND MY COMMUNITY CAME TOGETHER AND WE ACTIVATED
TO GET CITY HALL TO PUT A BUILDING OVER THE POOL ITSELF.
BY ME SEEING THAT IN THE EARLY AGE IT REALLY INSPIRED ME TO DO
SO AS WELL TO BE ADVOCATE INTERNALLY AND WHAT CHANGES I
CAN MAKE WITHIN SAN FRANCISCO. SO OVER THE YEARS I'VE DONE SO
I ALSO WANT TO SAY THANK YOU TO VICTORIA WEISS.
>> JULIE CHRIS BROWN FOR ENTRUSTING ME TO LEAD THE
STREETS OF SAN FRANCISCO TO MAKE THE MODERNIZATION OF THE
MODERN CHANGES THAT I'VE MADE WHETHER IT BE BIKE LANES,
WHETHER IT BE BUS LANES, WHETHER IT BE CROSSWALKS OR
STOP SIGNS. MY TEAM IN FACT THROUGHOUT THE
COVID AND DIFFERENT EVENTS HAVE ALWAYS BEEN IN THE FOREFRONT OF
MAKING THOSE CHANGES. I JUST WANT TO SAY THANK YOU TO
THE SUPERVISORS AS WELL AS TO MY FAMILY AND TO THE COMMUNITY
AND THANK YOU VERY MUCH
. >> ALL RIGHT.
AND I WOULD LIKE TO INVITE UP TOM HORN ALONG WITH HIS HUSBAND
OF 42 YEARS CESAR. >> ALL RIGHT.
I'M A OH SEE ROOSEVELT GUY. >> I WAS SUPPOSED TO CALL ON
YOU AFTER ME. >> ALL RIGHT, I GET ALL RIGHT.
>> SO YOU HAVE YOU HAVE FRIENDS AND FANS WHO ARE LINING UP TO
TO SPEAK ABOUT YOU AFTER I SPEAK.
I'M A BIG FAN OF TOM HORN'S AND IT IS A GREAT HONOR TO BE
ABLE TO RECOGNIZE HIM TODAY FOR HIS EXTRAORDINARY SERVICE OVER
MANY DECADES ADVOCATING FOR THE LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY, HIS WORK
TO ADVANCE CIVIL RIGHTS. HIS PHILANTHROPY AND HIS
COMMITMENT TO STRENGTHENING THE ARTS LONG BEFORE LGBTQ PLUS
RIGHTS GAINED MAINSTREAM ACCEPTANCE AND RECOGNITION.
TOM UNDERSTOOD THAT THE LAW COULD SERVE AS A POWERFUL TOOL
FOR PROTECTION AND JUSTICE AFTER HE GRADUATED FROM UCLA
LAW SCHOOL, HE BEGAN HIS CAREER AS A PUBLIC DEFENDER TAKING ON
CASES HIS PEERS WOULD NOT INCLUDING DEFENDING GAY MEN
BEING PROSECUTED UNDER SODOMY LAWS.
HIS ADVOCACY EVENTUALLY BROUGHT HIM TO THE ACLU WHERE HE TOOK
OVER AS LEGAL DIRECTOR OF ITS NEW MEXICO CHAPTER AS LEGAL
DIRECTOR. HIS WORK CHALLENGING SODOMY
LAWS THAT CRIMINALIZED GAY EXISTENCE WOULD HELP LAY THE
FOUNDATION ALONG WITH A LOT OF OTHER FOLKS FOR THE EVENTUAL
OVERTURNING OF THOSE LAWS ACROSS THE UNITED STATES
IN 2003 TOM MOVED TO SAN FRANCISCO IN 1976.
WE ARE LUCKY FOR IT AND HE HAS CONTINUED HIS WORK DEFENDING
PEOPLE TARGETED BY INSTITUTIONAL HOMOPHOBIA
AND WORKING TO OVERTURN OUTDATED AND UNJUST LAWS.
RECOGNIZING THE LASTING THAT LASTING LEGAL PROTECTIONS
REQUIRE POLITICAL POWER AND OR AND COMMUNITY ORGANIZING.
HE GOT INVOLVED WITH THE BUDDING GAY RIGHTS MOVEMENT
IN SAN FRANCISCO WORKING ALONGSIDE LEADERS LIKE HARVEY
MILK TO ENSURE THAT THE COMMUNITY WOULD NO LONGER BE
IGNORED BY THOSE IN POWER. THE MORNING AFTER THE WHITE
KNIGHT RIOTS, TOM ARRIVED AT THE COURTHOUSE WITH SEVERAL
OTHER LAWYERS TO DEFEND THE MANY GAY ACTIVISTS THAT HAD
BEEN ARRESTED FOR PROTESTING THE OUTRAGEOUSLY LENIENT
SENTENCE GIVEN TO HARVEY MILK'S ASSASSIN.
>> THAT COLLECTION OF LAWYERS WOULD BECOME THE BAKER BARRY
LAWYERS FOR VISUAL FREEDOM OR BAILIFF.
NOW THE NATION'S OLDEST AND LARGEST ASSOCIATION OF
LGBTQ PLUS LEGAL PROFESSIONALS .
>> OF COURSE TOM'S LEADERSHIP HAS EXTENDED FAR BEYOND THE
COURTROOM. IN 1981, THEN-MAYOR DIANNE
FEINSTEIN APPOINTED TOM TO THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO WAR MEMORIAL AND PERFORMING ARTS CENTER.
WE WILL NOT BE ADDING TERM LIMITS TO THE WAR MEMORIAL
BOARD. FRIENDS AT THE TIME TOM WAS ONE
OF ONLY THREE GAY COMMISSIONERS IN THE CITY.
HE OVERSAW THE RESTORATION OF THE HISTORIC WAR MEMORIAL OPERA
HOUSE AND CHAMPIONED GREATER INCLUSIVITY IN THE ARTS
INCLUDING SPONSORING SAN FRANCISCO OPERA'S FIRST EVER
PRIDE CONCERT CONCERT. AND HE CURRENTLY SERVES AS
PRESIDENT OF THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES.
>> AT THE HEIGHT OF THE HIV AIDS EPIDEMIC, TOM STEPPED
FORWARD. HE JOINED THE BOARD OF THE
KAPOSI'S SARCOMA KAPOSI'S SARCOMA EDUCATION AND RESEARCH
FOUNDATION WHICH WOULD BECOME THE SAN FRANCISCO AIDS
FOUNDATION. THERE HE HELPED RAISE AND AND
DIRECT RESOURCES TOWARD LIFESAVING RESEARCH, EDUCATION
AND COMPASSIONATE CARE DURING ONE OF THE CITY'S DARKEST
MOMENTS AFTER THE DEATH OF HIS FRIEND AND BAY AREA REPORTER
FOUNDER BOB ROSS. TOM STEPPED UP AGAIN TO SERVE
AS PUBLISHER OF THE BAY AREA REPORTER BETWEEN 2004 AND 2013.
IN THAT ROLE HE HELPED PRESERVE ONE OF THE NATION'S MOST
IMPORTANT LGBTQ PLUS NEWSPAPERS ENSURING THAT THE COMMUNITY'S
STORIES, STRUGGLES AND TRIUMPHS ARE DOCUMENTED AND SHARED.
HE HAS ALSO SERVED AS PRESIDENT OF THE BOB ROSS FOUNDATION
SUPPORTING HIV AIDS SERVICES, LGBT Q PLUS CIVIL RIGHTS
ORGANIZATIONS AND CULTURAL INITIATIVES.
THROUGHOUT SAN FRANCISCO INCLUDING THE TWIN PEAKS PINK
TRIANGLE THAT GOES UP EVERY JUNE IN HONOR OF PRIDE.
>> AND IT IS IN THIS ROLE THAT WE HAVE ALL BENEFITED BECAUSE
THE BOB ROSS FOUNDATION PAYS FITS THE BILL FOR ALL OF OUR
PRIDE AND OTHER LGBTQ CELEBRATIONS.
OVER IN THE MAYOR'S BALCONY. SO THANK YOU FOR THAT AS WELL.
>> TOM IS ALSO A COMMITTED INTERNATIONALIST AND A AND A
FRANCOPHILE TO BOOT. >> HE HAS HELPED CREATE AND AND
CHAIRED THE SAN FRANCISCO PARIS SISTER CITY COMMITTEE.
HE WAS INSTRUMENTAL IN ESTABLISHING BILL A SAN
FRANCISCO AND ARTIST RESIDENCY PROJECT.
THE REPUBLIC OF FRANCE HAS GIVEN TOM NUMEROUS RECOGNITIONS
FOR HIS WORK. AND IN 2021 HE WAS AWARDED THE
LEGION OF HONOR BY PRESIDENT EMMANUEL MACRON.
AND THAT IS THE HIGHEST AWARD FRANCE HAS TO GIVE.
ADDITIONALLY, PRINCE ALBERT THE SECOND THE PRINCE OF MONACO
APPOINTED TOM HONORARY CONSUL GENERAL OF MONACO IN SAN
FRANCISCO IN 2029 ENSURING AN ENDLESS STREAM OF PAPERWORK FOR
TOM HORN TO DO FOR FOLKS WHO MAY BE VISITING FROM MONACO.
TOM HORN YOU'RE GOING TO HEAR FROM SOME OF MY COLLEAGUES BUT
WE LOVE YOU TO PIECES. WE'RE GRATEFUL FOR YOU.
YOU HAVE LOTS MORE TO DO. SO YOU KNOW, DON'T LET THIS BE
A PERMISSION TO LIKE TO LET UP BECAUSE BECAUSE WE'RE LOOKING
FORWARD TO YOUR CONTINUED CONTRIBUTIONS.
BUT WE WANTED TO GIVE YOU A LITTLE BIT OF WELL-DESERVED
AND LONG OVERDUE HONORING FOR THIS PRIDE.
WITH THAT SUPERVISOR MELDER THANK YOU.
>> PRESIDENT MANDELL. AND THANK YOU FOR HONORING TOM
HORN. AND I AM A BIG FAN OF TOM
HORN'S. I HAVE PERSONALLY BENEFITED.
YOU HAVE SAVED MY SKIN FOR YOUR WONDERFUL RELATIONSHIPS.
AND THANK YOU FOR RECOGNIZING HIS CONTRIBUTIONS BUT ALSO HIS
INTERNATIONALIST PROJECT. I DO HAVE MERCY UPON CAMILLE
FOR THAT SIMPLE. LA BACHATA DE SAN FRANCISCO.
I KNOW CITIES ARE BADLY OPPOSED TO SCHOOLS HAVE A FACEBOOK LIVE
LONGER SPONSORS YOU HAVE HOTELS AS STREETWISE OFFERS TO PLOW
THROUGH DONATED OR NO CPA. >> THERE'S SUPERVISOR DORSEY
THANK YOU PRESIDENT ELLEN. TOM I WANT TO ADD MY VOICE TO
THE PRAISE FOR EVERYTHING THAT YOU HAVE DONE FOR OUR COMMUNITY
AND FOR OUR CITY. BUT I THINK FOR ME ESPECIALLY I
WANT TO EXPRESS MY GRATITUDE THAT YOU TOOK THE HELM OF THE
BAY AREA. REPORTER AND I HAVE COME TO
REALIZE JUST HOW IMPORTANT HAVING A NEWS ORGANIZATION OF
THAT CALIBER TO RECORD THE EXTRAORDINARY HISTORY THAT THE
LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY HAS HAD IN THIS CITY.
I THINK MORE THAN ANY NEWS ORGANIZATION OR PUBLICATION
THAT I'M AWARE OF IN THIS CITY THERE'S MORE CONTINUITY
AND INSTITUTIONAL MEMORY FROM THE B.A.R.
AND I JUST HAVE OVER THE YEARS REALLY APPRECIATED THE
OPPORTUNITY TO WORK WITH ALL THE JOURNALISTS AND EDITORS
AND REPORTERS THERE. BUT IT WOULDN'T BE POSSIBLE
WITHOUT THE LEADERSHIP THAT YOU BROUGHT AND THE STABILITY THAT
YOU HAD AND WHAT YOU DID TO MAKE SURE THAT IT WAS DIGITIZED
AND PRESERVED FOR HISTORY. I THINK THAT IS A HISTORY THAT
IS REALLY GOING TO BE INFLUENTIAL.
>> SO THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP ON THAT.
>> TOM HORNE. THE FLOOR IS YOURS.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. PRESIDENT MANDELA AND MADAME LA
QUINCY MUNICIPAL SUPERVISOR DORSEY AND SUPERVISORS.
IT'S A GREAT HONOR TO BE HERE TODAY.
IT WAS ALMOST 50 YEARS TO THE DAY THAT I MOVED PERMANENTLY TO
SAN FRANCISCO IN 1976 AND I CAME HERE AS A YOUNG LAWYER
JUST WANTING TO BE WITH PEOPLE THAT WERE LIKE ME AND AND JUST
PLY MY MY MY MY TRADE. AND LITTLE DID I KNOW THAT OVER
THE COURSE OF THE NEXT 50 YEARS I WOULD BE DROPPED IN THE
CENTER OF THE POLITICAL AND CULTURAL HEART OF SAN
FRANCISCO AND IT TRULY HAS CHANGED HAS CHANGED MY LIFE.
AND I MET THE LOVE OF MY LIFE 42 YEARS AGO PLUS SO I'M VERY
GRATEFUL FOR THE KIND WORDS THAT ALL OF YOU HAVE SPOKEN
AND FOR THIS GESTURE. BUT I SIMPLY HAVE TO SAY THAT
WHAT I HAVE RECEIVED FROM SAN FRANCISCO IS SO MUCH GREATER
THAN ANYTHING I CAN EVER GIVE TO SAN FRANCISCO.
SO THANK YOU PRESIDENT MADELINE THANK YOU SUPERVISORS.
WE'VE GOT THREE SUPERVISORS HERE.
ALL RIGHT. I'M GETTING NEXT TO YOU.
AND THEN WE'LL GET THEM OVER THERE.
THANK YOU TO OUR ARTS AND CULTURE.
YEAH, I WORK BUT I WORK FOR HIM NOW.
>> BE GOOD TO HIM. ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS A. ALL RIGHT, SO.
>> MADAM CLERK, I THINK THAT TAKES US BACK TO COMMITTEE
REPORTS. PLEASE CALL ITEM 44.
>> ITEM 44 WAS CONSIDERED BY THE LAND USE AND TRANSPORTATION
COMMITTEE AT A REGULAR MEETING ON MONDAY, JUNE 1ST, 2026
AND WAS RECOMMENDED AS A COMMITTEE REPORT.
IT IS A RESOLUTION TO URGE STATE OFFICIALS TO SUPPORT
CALIFORNIA STATE SENATE BILL 436 THE KEEPING CALIFORNIANS
HOUSED ACT, WHICH SEEKS TO PREVENT DISPLACEMENT BY
EXTENDING THE NOTICE PERIOD FOR RENTERS TO PAY OR VACATE FROM
THREE DAYS TO 14 DAYS BRINGING CALIFORNIA IN LINE WITH OTHER
STATES. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM
44. SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN.
I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY AI SUPERVISOR MAHMUD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR AMENDMENT HI. AMENDMENT I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUDER SAUDER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I.
SUPERVISOR WANG WANG I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN EITHER
TONIGHT'S AND WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 45 ITEMS 45 THROUGH 48 WERE
CONSIDERED BY THE RULES COMMITTEE AT A REGULAR MEETING
ON MONDAY JUNE 1ST, 2026 AND WERE RECOMMENDED TO THE
FULL BOARD. ITEM 45 ITSELF IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO CREATE THE NORTH BEACH
ENTERTAINMENT ZONE THE FERRY BUILDING ENTERTAINMENT ZONE THE
BUILT IN PLACE DOWNTOWN ACTIVATION ZONE TO AUTHORIZE
THE OUTDOOR CONSUMPTION OF ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES DURING AN
ENTERTAINMENT ZONE EVENT STARTING AT 11 A.M. RATHER THAN
NOON AND AFFIRM THE SEQUEL DETERMINATION.
>> I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
AND PLEASE CALL ITEMS 46 TO 48 TOGETHER.
>> ITEM 46 WAS RECOMMENDED AS AMENDED WITH A NEW TITLE ADDING
THE NAME OF THE APPOINTEE. IT IS A MOTION TO CONFIRM THE
REAPPOINTMENT OF KEVIN BENEDICT DOE TERM ENDING APRIL 30TH 2032
THE POLICE COMMISSION ITEM 47 WAS RECOMMENDED AS AMENDED WITH
A NEW TITLE TO APPROVE THE MAYOR'S NOMINATION FOR THE
APPOINTMENT OF LAWRENCE LOWE TO THE POLICE COMMISSION FOR A
TERM ENDING APRIL 30TH 2030 AND ITEM 48 WAS AMENDED
RECOMMENDED AS AMENDED WITH A NEW TITLE TO APPROVE THE
MAYOR'S NOMINATION FOR THE REAPPOINTMENT OF MADI SCOTT TO
THE POLICE COMMISSION FOR A TERM ENDING APRIL 30TH, 2013.
>> AND WE CAN TAKE THESE SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MOTIONS ARE APPROVED AND LET'S GO TO ROLL
CALL. >> FIRST UP ON ROLL CALL FOR
INTRODUCTION TO TODAY IS SUPERVISOR CHEN.
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD THANK YOU SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN ALL RIGHT
. >> I HAVE TWO ITEMS TODAY.
FIRST I'M INTRODUCING ACTUALLY I HAVE SEVERAL ITEMS.
I'M GOING TO SUBMIT SOME OF THEM BUT I GOT TWO I'M GOING TO
TALK ABOUT ONE. I'M INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION TO
ADD THE COMMEMORATIVE STREET NAME DR. CARLOTTA TO HIT OR DEL
PORTILLO WAY TO THE SECTION OF BARTLETT STREET BETWEEN 21ST
AND 22ND. I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR
MELGAR FOR YOUR CO-SPONSORSHIP OF THIS.
THE BLOCK IS A HOME TO THE BACK SIDE OR DEPENDING ON YOUR
PERSPECTIVE IT IS ONE SIDE OF THE CITY COLLEGE SAN FRANCISCO
MISSION CAMPUS WHICH DR. DEL PORTILLO HELPED ESTABLISH
AND WHERE SHE SERVED AS DEAN FOR MANY YEARS.
DR. DEL PORTILLO IS A PIONEERING CIVIC LEADER WHOSE
DECADES OF PUBLIC SERVICE AND WORK AS A TEACHER,
COUNSELOR AND COLLEGE DEAN HELPED EXPAND EDUCATIONAL
ACCESS AND OPPORTUNITY FOR UNDERSERVED COMMUNITIES.
HER CAREER IN EDUCATION BEGAN IN 1972 WHEN SHE STARTED WORK
AS A COUNSELOR AT CITY COLLEGE'S SKILLS CENTER.
AT THE TIME, CITY COLLEGE HAD BEGUN OFFERING SOME CLASSES AT
VARIOUS LOCATIONS LOCATIONS IN THE MISSION DISTRICT.
DR. DEL PORTILLO RECOGNIZING THE IMPORTANCE OF SECURING A
PERMANENT HOME FOR PROGRAMS FOCUSED ON EDUCATION, JOB
TRAINING AND CITIZENSHIP IN THE MISSION WORKED ALONGSIDE OTHER
LATINO EDUCATORS TO ORGANIZE KEEPERS OF THE DREAM, A GROUP
DEDICATED TO ESTABLISHING A CITY COLLEGE CAMPUS IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD. THIS GROUP, WHICH GREW TO
INCLUDE COMMUNITY LEADERS, TEACHERS AND OTHER STAFF
ADVOCATED FOR ESTABLISHMENT OF THIS CAMPUS FOR DECADES
AND FINALLY ACHIEVED THAT WITH THE OPENING OF THE VALENCIA
MISSION CAMPUS IN 2007, DR. DEL PORTILLO SERVED AS DEAN OF THAT
CAMPUS FOR DECADES OVERSEEING INSTRUCTIONAL PROGRAMS
AND SUPPORTING GENERATIONS OF STUDENTS.
SHE OFTEN DESCRIBED IT AS HER FIFTH DAUGHTER.
SHE ARRIVED EARLY EACH DAY AND STAYED UNTIL THE LAST
MUTANT HAD LEFT AT THE MISSION CAMPUS RIBBON CUTTING CEREMONY
,HOUSE SPEAKER NANCY PELOSI JOINED DR. DEL PORTILLO TO
CELEBRATE THE MONUMENTAL ACHIEVEMENT REFLECTING ON THEIR
LONGSTANDING RELATIONSHIP AND RECALLING THAT HER FIRST
POLITICAL FUNDRAISER WAS HELD AT DR. DALE PORTEOUS DEL
PORTILLO'S HOME. >> SHE SERVED UNDER EVERY SAN
FRANCISCO MAYOR FROM GEORGE MOSCONE TO ED LEE AND BROKE
BARRIERS AS THE FIRST LATINA APPOINTED TO THE HUMAN RIGHTS
COMMISSION CIVIL RIGHTS COMMISSION AND FIRE COMMISSION.
SHE ALSO PLAYED A KEY ROLE IN INTEGRATING THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT AND IN 1990 SHE BECAME THE FIRST LATINA ELECTED
CITYWIDE TO THE SAN FRANCISCO UNIFIED DISTRICT BOARD OF
EDUCATION WITHOUT PRIOR APPOINTMENT AND WENT ON TO
SERVE TWO TERMS IN THAT REGARD SHE'S A LITTLE BIT LIKE
SUPERVISOR MELGAR DR. DEL PORTILLO ALSO HELPED FOUND THE
MEXICAN-AMERICAN POLITICAL ASSOCIATION IN SAN FRANCISCO
AND THE LATINO DEMOCRATIC CLUB AND WAS ACTIVE IN NUMEROUS
DEMOCRATIC CLUBS INCLUDING THE RAUL WALLENBERG DEMOCRATIC CLUB
AND THE ALICE B TOKLAS LGBTQ DEMOCRATIC CLUB.
IN ADDITION TO FOUNDING THE MISSION CAMPUS, SHE
CONSISTENTLY CHAMPIONED RESPONSES TO THE SOCIAL
AND ECONOMIC INEQUITIES OF THE MISSION AND THE BROADER CITY.
SHE CO-FOUNDED THE MISSION HIRING HALL, A NONPROFIT THAT
PROVIDES COUNSELING, TRAINING AND JOB PLACEMENT SERVICES FOR
LOW AND MODERATE INCOME SAN FRANCISCANS.
SHE SERVED ON THIS BOARD FOR MORE THAN 20 YEARS AND WAS A
DRIVING FORCE BEHIND PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT AND FUND
AND FUNDRAISING. SHE WAS ALSO INSTRUMENTAL
IN ESTABLISHING THE CONSTRUCTION ADMINISTRATION
AND TRAINING PROGRAM AT CITY COLLEGE AND THE WHICH IS NOW
THE CONSTRUCTION ADMINISTRATION PROFESSIONAL SERVICES ACADEMY
OR CASA AND HELPED OPEN PATHWAYS TO STABLE CAREERS FOR
THOUSANDS OF RESTAURANTS. >> SHE LED THE LATINO HISPANIC
FUNDRAISING COMMITTEE FOR THE MAINE PUBLIC LIBRARY WHICH
SPONSORED THE COMMUNITY MEETING ROOM AND AND COMMISSION TWO
THREE DIMENSIONAL MURALS CELEBRATING LATIN AMERICAN
LITERATURE AND HER LEGACY IS FURTHER HONORED IN DISTRICT
EIGHT IN THE GLENMORE PARK LIBRARY, WHICH BEARS HER NAME
IN ITS CHILDREN'S SECTION IN RECOGNITION OF HER
DEDICATION TO LITERACY AND COMMUNITY INVESTMENT
AND EVEN IN RETIREMENT SHE'S REMAIN DEEPLY COMMITTED
EDUCATIONAL EQUITY. IN 2010 SHE FOUNDED FRIENDS OF
THE MISSION CAMPUS, A FOUNDATION THAT HAS AWARDED
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS IN SCHOLARSHIPS TO CITY
COLLEGE STUDENTS TRANSFORMING LIVES THROUGH ACCESS TO
EDUCATION AND JOB TRAINING. >> THROUGHOUT HER LIFE SHE'S
EXEMPLIFIED THE VERY BEST OF CIVIC LEADERSHIP SERVING AS AN
ADVOCATE, MENTOR AND VOLUNTEER WHO'S ENDURING IMPACT CONTINUES
TO STRENGTHEN COMMUNITIES ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO.
THIS COMMEMORATIVE STREET NAMING IS A WAY TO HONOR HER
FOR THAT EXTRAORDINARY SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY.
I WANT TO THANK DR. JUANITA OWENS AS WELL AS DR. DEL
PADILLA'S FAMILY FOR CHAMPIONING THIS STREET
RENAMING AND WORKING WITH MY OFFICE ESPECIALLY GRACE WONG ON
THIS PROJECT. I ALSO WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR
FIELDER'S OFFICE FOR THEIR COLLABORATION.
THEY'VE BEEN SUPER HELPFUL AND AGAIN THANK YOU SUPERVISOR
HELGA FOR YOUR CO-SPONSORSHIP AND THEN SECONDLY COLLEAGUES I
AM INTRODUCING TODAY AN ORDINANCE TO STREAMLINE THE
PROCESS BY WHICH SAN FRANCISCO DESIGNATE LANDMARKS
AND HISTORIC DISTRICTS UNDER ARTICLES TEN AND 11 OF THE
PLANNING CODE A NUMBER OF US HAVE BEEN PURSUING LAND
MARKINGS OF VARIOUS INDIVIDUAL LANDMARKS AND DISTRICTS.
>> AND FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS PROCESS
,YOU KNOW THAT IT IS IT IS LONG AND ARDUOUS AND THERE ARE
MANY STEPS TO IT AND IT SHOULD BE LONG AND ARDUOUS WITH MANY
STEPS AND CAREFUL CONSIDERATION OF WHETHER THE BUILDINGS
AND POTENTIAL DISTRICTS BEING CONSIDERED ACTUALLY MERIT
DESIGNATION. BUT IN CONVERSATIONS WITH THE
PLANNING DEPARTMENT IT'S BECOME CLEAR THAT THERE ARE THERE'S A
LITTLE BIT OF STREAMLINING THAT WE COULD DO HERE THAT WOULD
MAKE MAKE THIS A LITTLE EASIER ON THE STAFF WHO ARE DOING THE
WORK AND ON ON THE BROADER COMMUNITY.
ONE CHANGE IS TO ALLOW THE HISTORIC PRESERVATION
COMMISSION TO INITIATE AND RECOMMEND APPROVAL OF A
PROPOSED DESIGNATION AT THE SAME HEARING RATHER THAN HAVING
MULTIPLE HEARINGS PROVIDED THE PROPER NOTICE HAS BEEN GIVEN
FOR BOTH ACTIONS UNDER OUR CURRENT LAW INITIATION
AND RECOMMENDATION ARE TREATED AS SEPARATE STEPS AND SO THEY
REQUIRE SORT OF DOUBLE VISITING CONSOLIDATING WHERE APPROPRIATE
WOULD ELIMINATE THAT REDUNDANT SPLIT IN WHAT'S GENERALLY A
SINGLE DECISION. THERE ARE OTHER CHANGES THAT
WE'LL DISCUSS AND LAND USE MORE TO CLEAN UP SEVERAL PROCEDURAL
REQUIREMENTS THAT HAVE ACCUMULATED OVER THE YEARS
AND ADD FRICTION TO THE DESIGNATIONS WITHOUT REALLY
SERVING ANY PARTICULAR PROCESS ANY PARTICULAR BENEFIT THAT THE
LEGISLATION DOES NOT CHANGE THE SUBSTANTIVE STANDARDS FOR
DESIGNATION OR THE CRITERIA FOR WHAT QUALIFIES AS A LANDMARK.
THE HISTORIC PRESERVATION COMMISSION'S AUTHORITY REMAINS
THE SAME. I THINK WE HAVE ONE OF THE MOST
ROBUST AND AND SERIOUS LANDMARK DESIGNATION PROCESSES PROBABLY
IN THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA. SO WE'RE GOING TO KEEP THAT
JUST MAKE IT A LITTLE BIT MORE USER FRIENDLY.
>> I DO WANT TO THANK RICH SUCRE, ALEX WESTHOFF, PILAR
LAVALLE AND THE REST OF THE PRESERVATION STAFF AND THE
PLANNING DEPARTMENT FOR THEIR ASSISTANCE IN HELPING WITH THIS
LEGISLATION. I WANT TO THANK S.F. HERITAGE
FOR THEIR REVIEW AND PARTNERSHIP.
>> I WANT TO THANK SOME OF THE COMMISSIONERS ON HISTORIC
PRESERVATION COMMISSION WHO'VE BEEN VERY ENGAGED.
I WANT TO THANK MY LEGISLATIVE AIDE RENELL BAJWA CALVIN
ACTUALLY DID SOME WORK ON THIS AS WELL WHEN HE WAS IN MY
OFFICE AND THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR MELGAR THANK YOU MADAM CLERK.
TODAY I HAVE TWO IN MEMORIAM AND I WOULD ASK THAT WE CLOSE
THIS MEETING IN MEMORY OF GEORGE DONGSHENG LIM WHO PASSED
AWAY PEACEFULLY ON MAY 19TH, 2026 AT SAN FRANCISCO CHINESE
HOSPITAL AFTER HIS BATTLE WITH BONE CANCER.
HE WILL BE REMEMBERED AS A FATHER GRANDFATHER, UNCLE,
GRAND UNCLE AND FRIEND TO MANY. HE IS SURVIVED BY HIS WIFE
IRENE HUEY SHA LIM ALONG WITH HIS OLDER SON VICTOR AND HIS
WIFE VIVIAN, HIS YOUNGER SON VINCENT AND TWO BEAUTIFUL
GRANDCHILDREN LEONARD AND ABIGAIL.
GEORGE WAS BORN IN TOI SHAN CHINA ON JUNE 5TH, 1953.
HE WAS A YOUNGER CHILD RAISED SINGLEHANDEDLY BY HIS MOTHER
MCHUGH LAO LIM. >> AT AGE FIVE HE IMMIGRATED TO
HONG KONG FROM CHINA BY WAY OF MACAO.
HE GRADUATED FROM PRIMARY SCHOOL BUT BECAUSE OF ACADEMIC
CONSTRAINTS, GEORGE ENDED HIS STUDIES EARLY AND STARTED
WORKING AFTER RECEIVING HIS IMMIGRATION VISA IN 1972.
GEORGE IMMIGRATED TO UNITED STATES ALONG WITH HIS SISTER'S
FAMILY ON DECEMBER 27TH, 1979 TO REJOIN THEIR FATHER
AND MOTHER IN SAN FRANCISCO. HE ENROLLED IN SAN FRANCISCO
ADULT SCHOOL STUDYING ESL AND TOOK VARIOUS COURSES AT
CITY COLLEGE. GEORGE BECAME CLOSE FRIENDS
WITH MATT AND MANY OF HIS IMMIGRANT CLASSMATES.
HE BECAME FLUENT IN ENGLISH AND IN ADDITION TO CHINESE,
GEORGE OFTEN HELPED TRANSLATE AND EXPLAIN OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS
BACK AND FORTH PROVIDING SUPPORT FOR ANY IMMIGRATION,
EMPLOYMENT OR LEGAL NEEDS. HIS RELATIVES AND FRIENDS
FACED. IN 1979 GEORGE MARRIED HIS WIFE
IRENE IN HONG KONG. AFTER IRENE IMMIGRATED TO THE
U.S. THEY RAISED TWO SONS VICTOR AND VINCENT IN NORTH
BEACH. GEORGE LOVED HIS FAMILY
AND EMPHASIZED THE IMPORTANCE OF CHINESE LANGUAGE AND CULTURE
WITH HIS CHILDREN AND OFTEN READ THE CHINESE NEWSPAPERS
AND BOOKS TO VICTOR. HE ALSO LOVED SPENDING TIME
WITH HIS GRANDCHILDREN, PLAYING GAMES AND EXPLORING
NEIGHBORHOOD EVENTS WITH THEM. GEORGE WORKED AS A BUSBOY
WAITER, CLERK, TYPEWRITER REPAIR SPECIALIST, BARTENDER
AND GARMENT FACTORY TAILOR IN MANY LOCATIONS INCLUDING AT
THE RENOWNED CANTONESE OPERA SINGERS LAU KIM LONG KIM LING
RESTAURANT THE HISTORIC MING'S RESTAURANT IN PALO ALTO
CHINATOWN'S FAR EAST CAFE FOR HIS RESTAURANT U.S. POST DOLE'S
RINCON ANNEX AND VARIOUS GARMENT FACTORIES IN THE BAY
AREA. IN HIS LATER YEARS HE SERVED AS
AN IN-HOME SUPPORT SERVICE WORKER SUPPORTING HIS PARENTS
IN LAW. GEORGE LOVED TO HANG OUT
IN CHINATOWN DURING HIS SPARE TIME PLAYING CHESS AT SAN
FRANCISCO'S CHINESE CHESS ASSOCIATION AND SUPPORT
PORTSMOUTH SQUARE WITH HIS FRIENDS.
HE ALSO FREQUENTED THE LOCAL LIBRARY TO READ CURRENT EVENTS
AND LATEST STOCK DEVELOPMENTS. HE OVERCAME MANY HEALTH
CHALLENGES INCLUDING BEATING GASTRIC CANCER DURING THE
PANDEMIC WITH CHEMOTHERAPY AND SURGERY BUT UNFORTUNATE LEE
THE CANCER METASTASIZED LAST YEAR CAUSING HIS HEALTH TO
DECLINE RAPIDLY. GEORGE XING LIM WILL BE GREATLY
MISSED BY HIS FAMILY. ALL OF HIS RELATIVES
AND FRIENDS. HE WOULD HAVE TURNED 73 THIS
FRIDAY. I WANT TO EXPRESS MY DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO VICTOR LIM. A FRIEND FORMER FELLOW BOARD
AIDE NOW WITH THE PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT.
HIS WIFE VIVIAN POH AND THEIR WHOLE FAMILY.
MY SECOND IN MEMORIAM IS FOR TONY FAZIO ALONG WITH PRESIDENT
RAFAEL MANDOLIN. IT IS WITH GREAT SADNESS THAT
WE MOURN THE PASSING OF ANTHONY TONY FAZIO, A BELOVED HUSBAND,
FATHER, GRANDFATHER, FRIEND, MENTOR AND ONE OF SAN
FRANCISCO'S MOST INFLUENTIAL POLITICAL STRATEGISTS.
>> FOR NEARLY FIVE DECADES, TONY WAS WOVEN INTO THE FABRIC
OF SAN FRANCISCO CIVIC LIFE. AFTER ARRIVING IN SAN FRANCISCO
IN 1968 AND GRADUATING FROM SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY, HE
DEDICATED HIMSELF TO ORGANIZING COMMUNITIES, STRENGTHENING
LABOR MOVEMENTS, SUPPORTING NONPROFIT ORGANIZATIONS
AND HELPING SHAPE THE POLITICAL LANDSCAPE OF SAN FRANCISCO.
TONY'S PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS WERE
EXTRAORDINARY AS A FOUNDER OF WINNING DIRECTIONS.
HE HELPED REDEFINE POLITICAL DIRECT MAIL IN CAMPAIGN
COMMUNICATIONS EARNING NATIONAL RECOGNITION AND IN MORE THAN
100 PALI AWARDS. HIS EXPERTISE, CREATIVITY
AND STRATEGIC VISION INFLUENCED HUNDREDS OF CAMPAIGNS ACROSS
THE COUNTRY AND HELPED TRAIN GENERATIONS OF POLITICAL
PROFESSIONALS. TONY'S COMMITMENT TO SERVICE
EXTENDED FAR BEYOND POLITICS. AS CHAIR OF THE BOARD OF
MISSION LANGUAGE VOCATIONAL SCHOOL MVS, HE HELPED CREATE
OPPORTUNITIES FOR COUNTLESS SAN FRANCISCANS SEEKING EDUCATION,
JOB TRAINING AND A PATHWAY TO A BETTER FUTURE.
HE REMAINED DEVOTED TO CAUSES THAT UPLIFTED WORKING PEOPLE
IN UNDERSERVED COMMUNITIES THROUGHOUT HIS LIFE.
TONY ALONGSIDE WITH HIS WIFE MARIE JOBLING AND SANDIE
AND JEFF MOREY LED THE DETERMINED GROUP THAT HELPED
HIM VISION IN ADVANCE WHAT BECAME SAN FRANCISCO'S DIGNITY
FUND A LANDMARK COMMITMENT TO ENSURING DEDICATED FUNDING
AND SERVICES FOR OLDER ADULTS AND PEOPLE WITH DISABILITY AS
THEIR WORK HELPED CREATE LASTING STRUCTURAL SUPPORT FOR
COMMUNITIES THAT ARE TOO OFTEN OVERLOOKED IN CITY BUDGETING
AND POLICY DECISIONS. THE IMPACT OF THAT EFFORT
CONTINUES TO BE FELT EVERY DAY ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO MY FORMER COWORKER, HIS WIFE MARIE
JOBLING AND HIS CHILDREN AMY, JOEY AND BECKY.
WE ARE GRATEFUL FOR TONY'S LIFETIME OF SERVICE AND FOR THE
EXAMPLE HE SAT THROUGH A LIFE DEDICATED TO HELPING OTHERS.
THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MELGAR. SUPERVISOR SAUDER THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHERYL SMITH. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WALTON. SUBMITTED.
THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR WONG.
COLLEAGUES TODAY I WOULD LIKE TO TAKE A MOMENT TO HONOR THE
LIFE OF MICHAEL DURAND WHO PASSED AWAY ON MAY 30TH 2026 AT
THE AGE OF 70. I'M JOINED BY MY COLLEAGUE
SUPERVISOR CHEN IN RECOGNIZING MICHAEL THROUGH TODAY'S
IN MEMORIAM. SUPERVISOR CHEN ALSO WORKED
CLOSELY WITH MICHAEL FOR MANY YEARS AND I'LL SHARE A FEW
WORDS AFTER HER ROLL CALL REMARKS.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SUPERVISOR CHAN.
>> THANK YOU COLLEAGUES AND THANK YOU.
YES. JOINED BY SUPERVISOR ALAN WONG.
I WOULD LIKE TO ADJOURN TODAY'S MEETING IN MEMORY OF MICHAEL
DURAN WHO PASSED AWAY MAY 30TH OF 2026.
MICHAEL WAS A PUBLISHER, EDITOR VIDEOGRAPHER, PHOTOGRAPHER
AND A MUSICIAN BASED IN SAN FRANCISCO.
ALTHOUGH MICHAEL WAS BORN AND RAISED IN LONG ISLAND, NEW
YORK, THE WEST SIDE OF SAN FRANCISCO IS HIS HOME AND WHERE
HE HAD SPENT THE MAJORITY OF HIS LIFE BEFORE DEVOTING HIS
CAREER TO JOURNALISM, HE WORKED AS A PHOTOGRAPHER AND EVENTS
PRODUCER TRAVELING THE WORLD. IN FACT HE WAS A COLLEAGUE TO
MY SISTER IN LAW TRAVELING AROUND THE WORLD TOGETHER AS
EVENT PRODUCER. SO HE CERTAINLY WAS A CLOSE
FAMILY FRIEND. >> HE PURCHASED THE RICHMOND
REVIEW AND SUNSET BEACON NEWSPAPERS IN 2019 AFTER
WORKING WITH FOUNDER PAUL KOH'S WHISKEY IN HIS TENURE AS
PUBLISHER AND EDITOR IN CHIEF OF THE RICHMOND REVIEW
AND SUNSET BEACON. HE GREW THE SIZE OF THE PAPER
AND THE TEAM OF PEOPLE CREATING THEM.
NOW THERE ARE MORE THAN 50 CONTRIBUTING EDITORS WRITERS
AND PHOTOGRAPHERS WHO WORK TO PUT BOTH PAPERS TOGETHER EACH
MONTH MANY OF WHOM ARE STUDENTS INTERNS FROM LOCAL HIGH SCHOOLS
AND COLLEGE PROGRAMS. MICHAEL BROUGHT THE PAPERS TO
SOCIAL MEDIA AND ONLINE TO RICHMOND SUNSET NEW STARCOM
AMASSING ONLINE ADVERTISEMENTS AND A MONTHLY ONLINE READERSHIP
OF MORE THAN 25,000 PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD.
HE PAVED THE WAY FOR NEW STREAMS OF REVENUE FOR THE
LOCAL PUBLICATIONS INCLUDING PATRON ACCOUNT WHERE NEIGHBORS
AND LOCAL BUSINESS COULD SUPPORT THIS COMMUNITY EFFORT
IN A TIME WHEN WHEN THE COVID 19 PANDEMIC SHUT OR MANY
NEIGHBORHOOD PAPERS. MICHAEL'S LEADERSHIP ENSURED
THAT RESIDENTS OF SAN FRANCISCO ESPECIALLY THOSE IN THE WEST
SIDE WOULD NOT GO WITHOUT ACCESS TO FREE QUALITY
JOURNALISM BY AND FOR OUR COMMUNITY.
IN ADDITION TO HIS CAREER, MICHAEL WAS A BELOVED FRIEND
BROTHER MENTOR, TALENTED MUSICIAN AND SUPPORTER OF HIS
COMMUNITY. HE WILL BE GREATLY MISSED
AND AND MICHAEL CERTAINLY WILL BE MISSED.
THE LAST TIME MICHAEL MADE A VIDEO A PERSONAL VIDEO SENT TO
ME WAS HIM PLAYING PIANO FOR HIS KNEE FOR HIS NIECE DURING
THE THANKSGIVING. AND THAT IS THE KIND OF PERSON
THAT MICHAEL WAS AND SO BELOVED AND SO KIND.
AND NICK'S COLLEAGUES I WANT TO WANTED TO RECOGNIZE AND HONOR
ONE OF OUR LONGTIME CITY WORKERS WHO PASSED AWAY
RECENTLY. VINCENT MICHAEL WILLIAMS MOVED
TO SAN FRANCISCO AFTER SERVING IN THE U.S. NAVY AND SPENT THE
REST OF HIS LIFE HERE FOR FOUR DECADES.
HE CONTINUED HIS LIFE OF PUBLIC SERVICE AT THE ASSESSOR'S
OFFICE WHERE HE SERVED AS A SHOP STORE FOR HIS FELLOW SEIU
LABOR SIBLINGS EVENTUALLY RISING THROUGH THE RANKS TO
BECOME THE FIRST AFRICAN-AMERICAN CHIEF OF
TECHNICAL SERVICES. DESPITE BEING BORN
IN PITTSBURGH, PENNSYLVANIA, VINCENT WAS A SAN FRANCISCAN AT
HEART STAYING FAITHFUL TO HIS FAVORITE FOODS THE SEVEN MILE
HOUSE BURGER AND ORIGINAL JOE'S BUTTER CAKE.
VINCENT PASSED AWAY PEACEFULLY ON APRIL 29TH AFTER A
WELL-LIVED LIFE AT THE RIPE AGE OF 77.
IN HIS HONOR WE WOULD LIKE TO POSTHUMOUSLY DECLARE HIS
BIRTHDAY MARCH 24TH, 2026. AS VINCENT MICHAEL WILLIAMS DAY
AND THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN. >> SEEN NO OTHER NAMES ON THE
ROSTER? MR. PRESIDENT, I WANT TO MAKE
SOME REMARKS. >> SUPERVISOR WONG IN Q
SUPERVISOR OR CHEN. COLLEAGUES TODAY I WOULD LIKE
TO TAKE A MOMENT TO HONOR THE LIFE OF MICHAEL DURAND WHO
PASSED AWAY LAST SATURDAY. LIKE SUPERVISOR CHEN, I WORKED
CLOSELY WITH MICHAEL FOR MANY YEARS.
MICHAEL WAS MANY THINGS A PUBLISHER, EDITOR, PHOTOGRAPHER
,MUSICIAN, MENTOR AND STORYTELLER.
HE WAS ALSO A LONG TIME DISTRICT FOUR RESIDENT.
BUT FOR MANY OF US ON SAN FRANCISCO'S WEST SIDE HE WAS
THE PERSON WHO HELPED PRESERVE THE IDENTITY OF OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS THROUGH THE PAGES OF THE SUNSET BEACON AND THE
RICHMOND REVIEW. MICHAEL CHRONICLED THE LIFE OF
OUR COMMUNITIES WHO CELEBRATE LOCAL ACHIEVEMENTS, HIGHLIGHTED
NEIGHBORHOOD CHALLENGES AND DOCUMENTED THE PEOPLE
AND INSTITUTIONS THAT MAKE THE SUNSET AND RICHMOND DISTRICT
SPECIAL. IN DOING SO HE CREATED A
LASTING RECORD OF WHO WE WERE, WHAT WE VALUED AND HOW OUR
COMMUNITIES EVOLVED OVER TIME. WHAT MADE MICHAEL'S WORK SO
MEANINGFUL WAS HIS UNDERSTANDING THAT THE STORIES
CLOSEST TO HOME MATTER. HE RECOGNIZED THAT A SCHOOL
PERFORMANCE, A SMALL BUSINESS OPENING A COMMUNITY EVENT OR A
LOCAL VOLUNTEER COULD BE JUST AS IMPORTANT TO RESIDENTS AS
ANY HEADLINE MAKING NATIONAL NEWS.
BECAUSE OF MICHAEL, COUNTLESS PEOPLE AND MOMENTS THAT MIGHT
OTHERWISE HAVE FADED WITH TIME WERE REMEMBERED.
>> THERE IS MUCH MORE THAT CAN BE SAID ABOUT MICHAEL'S LIFE
AND CONTRIBUTIONS. BUT TODAY I WANT TO EXPRESS MY
GRATITUDE FOR ALL THAT HE GAVE TO SAN FRANCISCO.
HIS WORK STRENGTHENED THE BONDS THAT CONNECT NEIGHBORS TO ONE
ANOTHER AND FOSTERED A DEEPER APPRECIATION FOR THE
COMMUNITIES WE CALL HOME. ON BEHALF OF THE RESIDENTS OF
DISTRICT FOR THE COMMUNITY, MICHAEL CALLED HOME FOR SO MANY
YEARS I EXTEND MY DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO MICHAEL'S
FAMILY, ESPECIALLY HIS SISTER BONNIE AS WELL AS HIS FRIENDS,
COLLEAGUES AND ALL THOSE WHOSE LIVES HE TOUCHED.
MAY WE HONOR HIS MEMORY BY CONTINUING TO INVEST IN OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS. SUPPORT LOCAL JOURNALISM
AND CELEBRATE THE PEOPLE WHOSE STORIES HELPED DEFINE OUR CITY.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WONG. >> MR. PRESIDENT, LET'S GO TO
PUBLIC COMMENT. AT THIS TIME THE BOARD WELCOMES
YOUR PUBLIC COMMENT. PLEASE LINE UP ON THE RIGHT
HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER ALONG THE CURTAINS.
YOU MAY SPEAK TO THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED ITEMS 51 AND 52 THE
ITEMS ON THE FLOOR ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE
AGENDA AND GENERAL MATTERS NOT ON TODAY ARE NOT ON THE
PUBLISHED AGENDA BUT MUST BE WITHIN THE BOARD'S SUBJECT
MATTER JURISDICTION. WILL THE FIRST SPEAKER COME
FORWARD? >> EVERYONE WILL BE PROVIDED
TWO MINUTES. >> HELLO EVERYONE.
THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME HERE TODAY.
I'M HERE TO INFORM AND ASK FOR A BUDGET TO BE SET ASIDE FOR
RESEARCH ON THE ENVIRONMENTAL AND HEALTH IMPACTS OF DATA
CENTERS AS WELL AS THE BEST POLICIES TO MITIGATE THESE
IMPACTS. I FIRST WOULD LIKE TO START
WITH A REPORT FROM THE KAPOOR FOUNDATION WHICH REPORTED ON
HOW DATA CENTERS ARE DISPROPORTIONATELY PLACED
IN ALREADY VULNERABLE AND MARGINALIZED COMMUNITIES.
WITH THAT BEING SAID, WE DO HAVE A DATA CENTER ALREADY
IN BAYVIEW WHICH HAS BEEN KNOWN TO BE LARGELY BLACK AND BROWN.
>> PEOPLE PUSHED INTO THAT COMMUNITY.
>> WE ALSO HAVE A DATA CENTER IN PHI DEI.
>> SOME REALLY CONCERNING STATS ON WHAT DATA CENTERS ARE
CONSUMING. THEY CONSUME ABOUT PER YEAR
ENOUGH ELECTRICITY TO FUEL THE STATE OF OHIO.
>> SO THAT'S 176 TERAWATTS PER HOURS AND THAT'S FROM THE
DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY REPORT IN 2023.
>> AND BY THE ENVIRONMENTAL, ENVIRONMENTAL AND ENERGY STUDY
INSTITUTE, THEY REPORT THAT DATA CENTERS CONSUME 5 MILLION
GALLONS A DAY WHICH IS ENOUGH TO PROVIDE 10 TO 50,000 PEOPLE
IN A TOWN. >> AND SO WITH THESE THERE ARE
A LOT OF CONCERNS ENVIRONMENTALLY ON AIR
POLLUTION, HEAT EXPOSURE FOREVER CHEMICALS, NOISE
POLLUTION AND WATER STREAM. ALL OF WHICH AFFECTS PEOPLE'S
HEALTH RESPIRATORY HEART DISEASES, REPRODUCTIVE
ENDOCRINE SLEEP DISTURBANCES AND SO MANY MORE THAT WE
ALREADY KNOW BASED ON DATA THAT'S OUT THERE.
SO I WOULD LIKE FOR A BUDGET TO BE SET ASIDE FOR THE RESEARCH
AND POSSIBLY DISCLOSURE OF PROPOSED DATA CENTERS BILLING
THE COMPANIES NOT THE COMMUNITIES.
AND MORE PUBLIC DISCUSSIONS AROUND THIS.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
PETER WARFIELD AM HEAD OF LIBRARY USERS ASSOCIATION
AND P.O. BOX 170544 SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA
94117-0544. AND LIBRARY USERS 2004 AT
PROTON MAIL.COM. >> POPE LEO THE 14TH HAS VERY
RECENTLY PUBLISHED AN ENCYCLICAL CONCERNING AI
AND THE NEED FOR IT TO BE FOR HUMANITY AND HUMAN VALUES NOT
JUST PROFIT. AND WE ARE MORE AND MORE
BECOMING AWARE AS WE READ ABOUT ALL SORTS OF VERY SERIOUS
ISSUES INCLUDING WHAT THE SPEAKER HAS MENTIONED WITH
REGARD TO ENVIRONMENT, HEAVY USE OF ELECTRICITY AND WATER
AND LAND AND DOWN TO INDIVIDUAL USE FOR EXAMPLE HELPING
TEENAGERS COMMIT SUICIDE WHICH THE NEW YORK TIMES REPORTED ON
LAST FALL AND OTHERS HAVE AS WELL.
UNFORTUNATELY THE LIBRARY WHOSE BUDGET YOU WILL SHORTLY BE
APPROVING OR HAS MOSTLY UNCRITICALLY TOUTED TECH
AND USE OF TECH EXPOSING LIBRARY USERS AND THE REST OF
OUR COMMUNITY AND THE WORLD TO A HOST OF SERIOUS POTENTIAL
AND ACTUAL PROBLEMS. >> AND THE LIBRARY
UNFORTUNATELY HAS REPEATEDLY VIOLATED OPEN GOVERNMENT LAW TO
DISCOURAGE AND SHRINK PUBLIC COMMENT ABOUT WHAT IT'S BEEN
DOING WITH RESPECT TO TECH AND OTHER THINGS AS WELL.
>> ON THE COMPLAINT OF A RETIRED LIBRARIAN ON THE
SUNSHINE TASK FORCE THREE MONTHS AGO RULED THAT THE
LIBRARY COMMISSION HAD FOR ABOUT A YEAR BEEN
SYSTEMATICALLY AND REPEATEDLY CUTTING THE TIME FOR PUBLIC
COMMENT UNLAWFULLY BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T WANT TO HEAR CRITICISM
FROM MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC THAT INCLUDED ABOUT TECH BUT IT ALSO
INCLUDED ABOUT POOR MORALE, BAD MANAGEMENT AND SO ON AND SO
FORTH. PLEASE KEEP THAT IN MIND AS YOU
DO THE BUDGET. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HELLO. MY NAME IS ALEX WOOD AND I LIVE
AT 24TH STREET AND OSAGE IN THE MISSION DISTRICT.
BEING SO CLOSE TO MISSION STREET IS EXCITING, CONVENIENT
AND ENTERTAINING. I LOVE THE MISSION.
IT'S MY HOME, MY APARTMENT IN THE MISSION ALSO HAS A
DIRECT VIEW OF OSAGE ALLEY BETWEEN THE RESTAURANT PAPRIKA
AND MISSION DANCE STUDIO AND THAT IS THE REASON WHY I'M
HERE TODAY. I'M NOT HERE TO DEMONIZE
UNHOUSED THE UNHOUSED OR PEOPLE FIGHTING ADDICTION BUT I AM
HERE TO HIGHLIGHT COMPOUNDING ISSUES I SEE RISING IN THE
MISSION NEIGHBORHOOD DOZENS AND DOZENS OF TIMES A DAY.
PEOPLE CHOOSE TO PUBLICLY URINATE, DEFECATE AND DEAL
AND ABUSE ILLICIT DRUGS IN OSAGE ALLEY EVERY SINGLE DAY
. I CANNOT STEP OUTSIDE WITHOUT
FIRST LOOKING TO AVOID PUDDLES OF HUMAN URINE AND PILES OF
HUMAN FECES. I CANNOT LEAVE MY WINDOW OPEN
BECAUSE THE SMELL OF URINE, FECES OR THE SMELL OF DRUG
SMOKE IS SO STRONG. EVEN WITH A PUBLIC RESTROOM
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET AT 24TH STREET PLAZA, PEOPLE STILL
CHOOSE TO QUICKLY RELIEVE THEMSELVES IN THE ALLEY ALONG
WITH THE LARGE AMOUNT OF HUMAN WASTE AND DRUG ABUSE.
I'VE ALSO WITNESSED PROSTITUTION AND MULTIPLE
PHYSICAL ASSAULTS. ON WEDNESDAY MAY 27TH THERE WAS
A MAN OUTSIDE MY WINDOW WITH HIS RED SWEAT PANTS PULLED DOWN
TO HIS ANKLES. WHEN I CALLED POLICE FOR HELP
THEY NEVER SHOWED UP AND THERE WAS NO FOLLOW UP.
IT MAKES ME WISH OFFICER TRAM AND CAPTAIN LEE WORKED IN MY
NEIGHBORHOOD. >> WHEN POLICE ARE PRESENT AT
THE BART PLAZA, THE CROWDS SELLING FENCE GOODS DO LEAVE
BUT OFTEN DRIFT INTO RESIDENTIAL STREETS OR IN MY
CASE OSAGE ALLEY TO ABUSE DRUGS.
I REGULARLY SEE CROWDS OF UP TO 8 OR 9 PEOPLE AT ONCE GATHERING
TO SMOKE CRACK FENTANYL OR OTHER ILLICIT DRUGS RIGHT
OUTSIDE MY BEDROOM WINDOW. THEY ALSO RELIEVE THEMSELVES
IN THE ALLEY AS WELL BECAUSE MY DISTRICT SUPERVISOR JACKIE
FIELDER IS NOT PRESENT. I AM ASKING THE DISTRICT
SUPERVISORS WHO ARE HERE FOR HELP.
I IMPLORE YOU TO LOOK INTO POSSIBLE WAYS THE CITY CAN
PREVENT OR DETER CRIMINAL ACTIVITY FROM REPEATING EVERY
SINGLE DAY IN OSAGE ALLEY. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> APOLOGIES FOR CUTTING YOU OFF.
WE ARE PROVIDING EVERYONE THE SAME TWO MINUTES.
NEXT SPEAKER GOOD AFTERNOON. >> BOARD PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN
AND BOARD MEMBERS. MY NAME IS RICHARD STEVE
PETERSON AND AGAIN I NOTE THE ABSENCE OF DISTRICT NINE
AND YOU'VE HEARD A RESIDENT SPEAK TO THAT VERY ISSUE.
I THINK THAT IN SOLIDARITY WITH THE SUPERVISOR NONE OF YOU
SHOULD BE GIVING AWARDS TO MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC OR
MEMBERS WITH THE THING UNTIL THAT ISSUE IS RESOLVED.
AND I DON'T KNOW WHERE YOUR LACK OF CIVIL SOLIDARITY CAME
FROM, BUT I THINK THAT YOU'VE CREATED A MONSTER BY THIS.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW SUPERVISOR FIELDER CAN SPONSOR LEGISLATION
LEGISLATION. WHEN SHE'S NOT PRESENT ARE AN
ABSTENTION. I WISH THE LEGAL DEPARTMENT
WOULD LOOK INTO THAT BUT I DO NOT.
ANOTHER LIGHTER ISSUE I AM HERE DUE TO A PLEA FOR THE RIGHT TO
SMOKE. SMOKING IS BECOMING DRACONIAN
AS YOU KNOW THAT OUR FORMER GOVERNOR SCHWARZENEGGER SMOKED
AND I THINK IT'S ACTUALLY A CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHT.
YOU MAY LAUGH BUT ON THE ON THE NEW YEAR'S DAY I WAS NOT ABLE
TO HAVE A BARBECUE WHICH I TRADITIONALLY DO BECAUSE THE
BARBECUE WOULD GIVE OFF SMOKE AND THE NIGHT BEFORE THE CITY
AND COUNTY HAD A HAD A FOURTH AND 4TH OF JULY HAD HAD A
FIREWORKS AND SO IT WAS LIMITED THE RIGHT TO SMOKE.
>> IT IS PRETTY CRITICAL BECAUSE WE HAVE POLITICIANS WHO
ARE IN LOS ANGELES WHO ARE LEGISLATING.
>> NOPE. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER. >> HI, GOOD AFTERNOON.
I'M BARRY TORONTO. >> HAPPY PRIDE AND GOOD LUCK TO
EVERYBODY WHO HAS SOMETHING ON THE BALLOT TODAY.
>> I MISS ANGELA. >> I HOPE SHE COMES BACK SOON.
AND ANYWAY, TWO ISSUES I WANT TO ADDRESS.
>> FIRST, I URGE YOU AGAIN TO DO ANOTHER RESOLUTION REGARDING
AUTONOMOUS VEHICLES. YOU SHOULD BE ABLE LOCALLY TO
HAVE SOME CONTROL SUCH AS A GEOFENCE.
WHEN YOU HAVE A MAJOR PARADE SUCH AS GAY PRIDE COMING UP
AND THEY'RE GOING TO STAY AWAY FROM THE CREATING TRAFFIC
SOMETIMES YOU GET A LINE OF SIX OR SEVEN OF THEM AT A TIME
AND THEY INTERFERE. >> AS YOU NOTICE NOW OFF THE
FREEWAYS THEY CAN'T DEAL WITH POTHOLES.
I THANK SUPERVISOR A SUPERVISOR FOR HOLDING HEARINGS ON THIS
ISSUE SO WORK WITH WITH HIM TO CREATE LEGISLATION AND TO DO A
RESOLUTION TO YOUR STATE LEGISLATORS TO TO WE ASK THAT
YOU CAN HAVE SOME CONTROL OVER IT.
>> CONTROL OVER POSSIBLY HAVING IT OPEN TO LOW INCOME PEOPLE
AND ALSO TO WHERE THEY CAN GO BECAUSE BECAUSE BECAUSE
AND ALSO THEY LEARN BAD BEHAVIOR OF OTHER DRIVERS
BECAUSE I'VE SEEN THEM DOING LEGAL TURNS ETC. SO IT'S NOT
LIKE THEY JUST FOLLOW THE LAW ALL THE TIME.
THEY HAVE A MINOR OF THEIR OWN WHICH I HOPE IT DOESN'T EXTEND
FURTHER OUT. WE WON'T GO THAT FAR.
THE NEXT ONE IS I COULDN'T HEAR BECAUSE THE SPEAKERS ARE NOT
ALWAYS WELL PLACED IN THIS ROOM.
IT'S BETTER TO HEAR THIS ONLINE BUT IRA SANDLER OWNED 1015
FOLSOM 1015 FOLSOM USED TO BE SOMETHING ELSE BEFORE THAT.
I WON'T SAY IT BECAUSE IT MIGHT OUT ME AT ALL BUT IT WAS A BUT
IT WAS CLOSED FOR A FEW YEARS DUE TO THE AIDS SCARE BUT THEN
HE TOOK IT OVER AND MADE IT THE BEST NIGHTCLUB IN THE 90S SO I
THINK HE SHOULD BE HONORED. I DON'T KNOW WHERE HE LIVED BUT
YOU SHOULD HONOR HIM. MAY HE REST IN PEACE.
THE CHRONICLE HAD A GREAT ARTICLE ABOUT HIM.
>> YOU SHOULD READ THE ARTICLE AND YESTERDAY'S PAPER
AND FIGURE OUT HOW TO HONOR THAT.
>> THANK YOU, MR. TORONTO YOUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HELLO. WITH WHAT I SAW DURING THIS
ELECTION CYCLE I HOPE THE MODERN DAY PLANTATION OWNERS
CEOS BILLIONAIRES DO NOT SUCCEED IN AIMING YOUR RAGE
AGAINST YOUR NEIGHBORS AND WE INSTEAD KEEP IT DIRECTED AT
THOSE THAT ARE ENACTING AND FUNDING STATE'S VIOLENCE
BECAUSE THERE IS NO ONE IN THE U.S. GOVERNMENT WHO HAS CLEAN
HANDS WHEN IT COMES TO SUPPORTING DOMESTIC STATE
VIOLENCE AGAINST OUR MOST VULNERABLE SUCH AS THE
DISABLED, HOMELESS AND IMPRISONED.
WE CANNOT EXCUSE NOR DEFY ANY U.S. GOVERNMENT REPRESENTATIVE.
AND HERE IS A SHORT LIST OF SOME ATROCITIES AMERICA AND THE
AMERICAN GOVERNMENT IS CURRENTLY COMMITTING.
THE U.S. GOVERNMENT IS STILL TRYING TO SUBJUGATE MEXICO
AND SOUTH AMERICA CURRENTLY STARVING CUBA, TRYING TO USE
KENYA AS A QUARANTINE ZONE FOR AMERICANS INFECTED WITH EBOLA.
SUPPLYING ARMS FOR ISRAEL'S GENOCIDE AGAINST PALESTINE.
SLAUGHTERING PEOPLE IN IRAN AND IN THE CARIBBEAN,
EXPLOITING SO MANY AFRICAN COUNTRIES FOR OUR CELL PHONES
AND . STRIPPING, VOTING PROTECTIONS
FROM BLACK AMERICANS AND ULTIMATELY ALL AMERICANS
DOES. I MEAN LET'S HOPE WE CAN
CONTINUE VOTING RIGHT? AMERICA IS IN FULL SWING
AND TORTURING PEOPLE AND CONCENTRATION CAMPS
AND PRISONS. AMERICA IS PUSHING RABID
MISOGYNY, RACISM, HOMOPHOBIA, TRANSPHOBIA, PHOBIA ESPECIALLY
VIA YOU KNOW, THESE A.I. BOTS AND SOCIAL MEDIA AND ALL THE
BOTS THAT FLOOD SOCIAL MEDIA POSTS.
AMERICA IS ALSO PARTAKING GREATLY IN DESTROYING OUR ONLY
HABITATS. >> WE HUMANS HAVE THE EARTH
WITH ALL THESE DATA CENTERS THAT WERE REFERENCED EARLIER.
ALL IN THE NAME OF PROFIT AND POWER.
>> ALSO LET'S KICK GEO GROUP OUT OF THE TENDERLOIN.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS. I WOULD LIKE TO BEGIN BY
THANKING YOU ALL FOR THE TIME AND ENERGY YOU COMMIT TO THE
BETTERMENT OF OUR CITY. MY NAME IS ALEX LEO AND I'M A
JUNIOR AT STEWART ALL HIGH SCHOOL.
I'VE LIVED IN NEW JERSEY. I'VE LIVED IN DISTRICT EIGHT.
JUST STEPS FROM THE MISSION FOR THE LAST 14 YEARS.
IN THAT TIME I'VE WATCHED THE FOOD LANDSCAPE IN MY
NEIGHBORHOOD CHANGE. SMALL MARKETS HAVE CLOSED
AND THE NEED IS BECOMING INCREASINGLY VISIBLE.
THE S.F. MARIN FOOD BANK CURRENTLY HAS A WAITLIST OF
ROUGHLY 6000 PEOPLE IN SAN FRANCISCO ALONE.
THAT IS NOT A CHARITY PROBLEM. IT IS A SYSTEM PROBLEM.
I'M NOT HERE TO ASK FOR MORE SPENDING.
I UNDERSTAND THAT THE CITY IS IN A TIGHT BUDGET YEAR.
I'M HERE TO ASK FOR TWO THINGS THAT DO NOT REQUIRE NEW FUNDS.
FIRST, STRONGER COORDINATION BETWEEN CITY DEPARTMENTS
AND NONPROFIT PARTNERS SO THAT RESOURCES ARE NOT DUPLICATED
AND FEWER PEOPLE ARE MISSED. SECOND, ACTIVE HELP FROM THIS
BOARD AND IDENTIFYING UNDERUTILIZED PUBLIC SPACES
THAT COULD SUPPORT COMMUNITY MARKETS, THE DIGNIFIED GROCERY
STORE AND FARMER'S MARKET STYLE THAT THE FOOD BANK IS
EXPANDING. ONE SAN FRANCISCO ALREADY
EVALUATES PUBLIC LAND FOR HOUSING TRANSPORTATION
AND RECREATION. FOOD ACCESS SHOULD BE A PART OF
THIS CONVERSATION. I'D RATHER LIVE IN A CITY WHERE
NONPROFIT RESPONSIBILITY GETS SMALLER EVERY YEAR BECAUSE
PUBLIC SYSTEMS WORK EFFECTIVELY.
I HOPE YOU'LL HELP US MOVE IN THAT DIRECTION.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER GO. GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS
AND CLERKS OF THE BOARD. HAPPY ELECTION DAY.
>> MY NAME IS JOYCE N AND I HAVE THE PRIVILEGE OF BEING THE
ACTING DIRECTOR FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO YOUTH COMMISSION.
I WILL BE SPEAKING ON THE AGENDA ITEM NUMBER 52 THIS YEAR
2026 MARKS THE 30TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE SAN FRANCISCO YOUTH
COMMISSION. THE COMMISSION IS JUST A LITTLE
OLDER THAN ME. IT WAS PUT ON THE BALLOT
IN 1995 AS PROPOSITIONS OF. AND 60% OF SAN FRANCISCANS SAID
YES THERE SHOULD BE A YOUTH COMMISSION IN THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO. THE INAUGURAL CLASS WAS SWORN
IN IN 19 96. >> OVER THE YEARS THE
COMMISSION ADVOCATED FOR A TRANSFORMATIVE JUSTICE
INCREASING YOUTH CIVIC ENGAGEMENT, MAKING OUR CITY
GOVERNMENT ACCESSIBLE TO ALL YOUTH AND OF COURSE FREE MUNI
FOR YOUTH WHICH BENEFITS SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE 18 AND UNDER
EVERY DAY SO THAT TRANSPORTATION IS NOT A BARRIER
FOR THEM TO GO TO SCHOOL, WORK AND EXPLORE SAN FRANCISCO.
THE COMMISSION ALSO HAS SO MANY ALUMNI WHO HAVE COMMITTED TO
PUBLIC SERVICE AFTER LEAVING THE COMMISSION TO CONTINUE
DOING GOOD WORK FOR COMMUNITIES ALL AROUND OUR CELEBRATION AS
THIS THURSDAY JUNE 4TH AT 5 P.M. AND THEN THE FLIGHT COURTS
DOWNSTAIRS. >> WE INVITE YOU ALL THE
CLERK'S OFFICE, YOUR LEGISLATIVE AIDES, OFFICE
VOLUNTEERS AND INTERNS TO JOIN US FOR THIS MOMENTOUS MILESTONE
. THE COMMISSION THANKS
SUPERVISOR MCGUIRE FOR INTRODUCING THE RESOLUTION TO
COME AND TO COMMEMORATE OUR 30TH ANNIVERSARY AND WE THANK
SUPERVISORS CHAN DORSEY CHEN, WALTON MAHMOOD AND SOUDER FOR
CO-SPONSORING. I URGE A UNANIMOUS YES ON THIS
RESOLUTION. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER PRESIDENT BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS MARK LEACH.
THESE ARE MY TEAMSTERS YOUR NURSE MANAGERS.
I'M HERE IN FRONT OF YOU TODAY AS A LAST RESORT HAS MADE A
DECISION TO REASSIGN NURSING LEADERSHIP.
WE CALLED FOR THE TYPICAL MEET AND CONFER AND ATTEMPTED TO
CONVINCE US THAT THEY WERE MAKING A MISTAKE.
THOSE MEETINGS HAVE PROVED POINTLESS.
THE CITY, THE CIVIL SERVICES PROCESS IS BROKEN AND NOBODY
IN LEADERSHIP HAS SHOWN ANY WILLINGNESS TO MODIFY THE
DECISION THAT'S BEEN MADE. M.S., H.
THAT STANDS FOR MATERNAL CHILD ADOLESCENT HEALTH.
NEARLY 100 YEARS OF SERVING SAN FRANCISCO'S MOTHERS AND BABIES
WITH A TEAM OF M.S. H AND COORDINATED CBOS DR. ZELL
MILLER WAS A CITY EMPLOYEE AT MCI.
BRIEFLY SHE LEFT TO RUN HER OWN CBO.
THAT CBO RELIES ON THE CITY AND MCI FOR FUNDING JUST LIKE
THE DOZEN OR SO OTHER CBOS DOING THE SAME EXACT WORK.
THEY ALL CARE ABOUT IMPROVING OUTCOMES FOR MOTHERS
AND BABIES. DR. MALALA HAS MADE A FULL TIME
JOB OF UNDERMINING THE LEADERSHIP AT MY AGE.
SHE FILED RELENTLESS INFORMATION REQUESTS, CHERRY
PICKED DATA AND PRESENTED TO THE MAYOR'S OFFICE THE HEALTH
COMMISSION AND SELECT MEMBERS OF THIS BOARD.
HER EFFORTS ARE NOW BEING REWARDED AS THE EPA HAS DECIDED
TO REASSIGN OVER 40 YEARS OF LEADERSHIP IN THIS PRACTICE
AREA TO COMPLETELY UNRELATED AREAS ELSEWHERE IN SOME OF THE
TOP NURSING LEADERS IN MSK. IT STARTED OUT AS CLIENTS OF
THESE PROGRAMS. THEY RAISED CHILDREN WHILE
PURSUING THEIR NURSING CAREERS .
THEY ARE NOW HIGHLY EDUCATED BLACK AND LATINA WOMEN WITH
MASTER'S DEGREES. THEY ARE LIVING ROLE MODELS FOR
THEIR CLIENTS. AND AS HARD AS IT MAY BE TO
HEAR THERE HAS BEEN A FAILURE IN LEADERSHIP.
A CBO RECEIVING CITY FUNDING MALIGNS YOUR WORKFORCE AND YOUR
LEADERSHIP NEVER TALKS TO THE EMPLOYEES.
THEY IGNORE THE CONCERNS AND REASSIGN THEM TO UNRELATED
NURSING ROLES. THE OPINIONS AND MANIPULATED
STATS WERE TAKEN AT FACE VALUE AND PERMANENT PEAKS.
NURSING EMPLOYEES ARE NOW BEING REASSIGNED UNDER THE GUISE OF
BUDGET SAVINGS. THIS DECISION IS A WASTE OF
TALENT AND A WASTE OF MONEY. WE ARE ASKING FOR RESPECT.
WE ARE ASKING EACH OF YOU FOR A CONVERSATION.
WE ARE ASKING TO BE ON THE BOARD OF SUPERVISOR COMMITTEE
AT THE HEALTH COMMISSION AGENDAS AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. THANK YOU.
GOOD AFTERNOON. BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS MEG BUCKWALTER. I MANAGED TWO OF THE HOME
VISITING TEAMS MARK MENTIONED FOR WOMEN AND CHILDREN IN SAN
FRANCISCO INCLUDING ONE SPECIFICALLY FOR PREGNANT WOMEN
TO ACCESS PRENATAL CARE AND BEGIN SUBSTANCE USE
TREATMENT. >> BOTH PROGRAMS DIRECTLY
SUPPORT THE MAYOR'S PRIORITIES AND THE NEW STRONG STARTS
INITIATIVE. ALSO MENTIONED BY MARK I'M HERE
BECAUSE PROPOSED CHANGES TO M.K AGE MATERNAL CHILD
AND ADOLESCENT HEALTH ARE BEING MADE WITHOUT THE RIGHT PEOPLE
AT THE TABLE AND WITH INFORMATION THAT AS YOU HAVE
ALREADY HEARD IS NOT ACCURATE. WE HAVE BEEN TOLD THESE CUTS
ARE BUDGET DRIVEN BUT I CAN TELL YOU DIRECTLY ON FRIDAY I
HAD TO SUBMIT MY BUDGET TO THE STATE.
WE HAVE LEFT MONEY ON THE TABLE.
WE WILL BE TURNING UNSPENT FUNDS TO THE STATE RATHER THAN
BEING ALLOWED TO MAINTAIN OUR STAFF.
THESE REDUCTIONS ARE NOT ONLY UNNECESSARY, THEY ARE AVOIDABLE
. THE PEOPLE WE SERVE ARE AMONG
THE MOST VULNERABLE IN THIS CITY PREGNANT PEOPLE, NEWBORNS,
FAMILIES FIGHTING TO STAY HEALTHY AND HOUSED.
>> I URGE YOU TO PAUSE THESE CHANGES AND BRING THE CORRECT
STAKEHOLDERS INTO THE CONVERSATIONS BEFORE ANY
DECISIONS ARE FINALIZED. >> BECAUSE I HAVE TO ASK YOU
WHAT WILL THIS CITY DO WHEN BABIES ARE BEING BORN ON THE
STREET AGAIN BECAUSE WE HAVE NOT HAD BABIES BORN ON THE
STREETS SINCE THE INCEPTION OF OUR PROGRAMS.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> BEFORE THE NEXT SPEAKER WE DO HAVE A BOARD RULE THAT
PROHIBITS AUDIO SETTLEMENTS OF OPPOSITION OR SUPPORT.
SO IF YOU WOULD LIKE YOU CAN SHOW YOUR SUPPORT FINGERS BUT
PLEASE WE WANT TO HEAR THE SPEAKER'S COMMENTS.
>> NEXT SPEAKER THIS DOESN'T MEET FOR SHORT PEOPLE SO I HAVE
TO MOVE IT DOWN. >> GOOD AFTERNOON MEMBERS OF
THE BOARD. MY NAME IS MICHELLE SAILORS
AND I AM A NURSE MANAGER WITHIN MDH WITHIN D P H.
I AM HERE TODAY BECAUSE I BELIEVE THIS BOARD DESERVES
ACCURATE INFORMATION BEFORE MAKING DECISIONS THAT WILL
AFFECT SOME OF OUR CITY'S MOST VULNERABLE RESIDENTS.
THE DATA AND NARRATIVE ABOUT PRETERM BIRTHS IN SAN FRANCISCO
THAT HAVE BEEN PRESENTED TO JUSTIFY PROPOSED CUTS TO MDH
AND HOME VISITING ARE INCOMPLETE AND IN CRITICAL WAYS
THEY ARE WRONG. BEFORE ANY VOTE IS TAKEN I
RESPECTFULLY OR JUST URGE THIS BOARD TO PAUSE AND EXAMINE WHAT
THE NUMBERS ACTUALLY SHOW HOME VISITING IS NOT OVERHEAD.
IT IS INTERVENTION. OUR PUBLIC HEALTH NURSES GO
INTO HOMES THAT CLINICS CANNOT REACH.
THEY IDENTIFY POST-PARTUM DEPRESSION BEFORE IT BECOMES A
CRISIS. THEY CONNECT FAMILIES TO
SERVICES BEFORE A CHILD WELFARE CASE IS EVER OPENED.
THEY REDUCE EMERGENCY ROOM VISITS, HOSPITALIZATIONS
AND LONG TERM COSTS THAT ARE THAT FALL SQUARELY ON THE
CITY'S BUDGET. THESE PROGRAM PROGRAMS DO NOT
SERVE PEOPLE. THEY SAVE MONEY, DO NOT JUST
SERVE PEOPLE. THEY SAVE MONEY.
THE RETURN ON INVESTMENT FOR EVIDENCE BASED HOME VISITING IS
WELL DOCUMENTED NATIONALLY AND OUR LOCAL OUTCOMES REFLECT
THAT. EVERY DOLLAR CUT TODAY WILL
COST THE CITY FAR MORE IN BOUNCE DOWN THE LINE
IN EMERGENCY SERVICES AND ACUTE CARE AND IN GENERATIONAL COSTS
OF UNTREATED NEED. WHAT IS ALSO BEING OVERLOOKED
IS THIS YOU CANNOT GUT THE STRUCTURE AND EXPECT THE
PROGRAMS TO STAND. BY REMOVING THE LEADERS
AND MANAGERS OF HOME VISITING THESE PROPOSED CHANGES ARE
PLACING THE PROGRAMS THEMSELVES IN DANGER AND WITH THEM THE
MOST VULNERABLE PEOPLE IN OUR COMMUNITY MOTHERS, NEWBORNS,
FAMILIES ALREADY ON THE EDGE. THE INFRASTRUCTURE THAT
SUPPORTS FRONTLINE NURSES IS NOT BUREAUCRACY.
IT IS THE BACKBONE THAT ENSURES SAFE AND CONSISTENT ACCOUNTABLE
CARE. I'M NOT HERE TO BE ADVERSARIAL
. I'M HERE BECAUSE THE PEOPLE
DOING THE WORK AND THE FAMILIES DEPENDING ON IT HAVE NOT HAD A
SEAT AT THE TABLE. >> WE ARE ASKING FOR ONE.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER THANK.
>> THANK YOU BOARD OF SUPERVISORS FOR THIS
OPPORTUNITY FOR US THE CITIZENRY TO SPEAK.
MY NAME IS BELOW. I'M AN ARTIST.
I'M A GRADUATE OF THE YALE SCHOOL OF ART.
I'M A LONGTIME RESIDENT OF THE BAY AREA.
I LOVE SAN FRANCISCO. I AM AN ARTIST WHO OWING TO
THIS TIME OF POLITICAL AND EXISTENTIAL CRISIS HAS HAD
TO PIVOT TO DOING SOCIAL JUSTICE ACTIVISM USING MY ART.
>> I HAVE CONNECTED WITH A REVAMPED ORGANIZATION KNOWN AS
STOP. I EIGHT HUNDRED VIP'S INCLUDING
LEADING EXPERTS IN THE FIELD OF I SIGNED A PUBLIC STATEMENT
IN OCTOBER OF LAST YEAR A STATEMENT PUT OUT BY THE
INSTITUTE OF LIFE CALLING FOR A STOP TO THE DEVELOPMENT OF
ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE SPECIFICALLY AGI FOR ARTIFICIAL
GENERAL INTELLIGENCE UNPRECEDENTED ARTIFICIAL
INTELLIGENCE, AUTONOMOUS IN NATURE.
>> I HAVE A BONE TO PICK REGARDING SAN FRANCISCO LIBRARY
SAN FRANCISCO A.I. WEEK'S PRESENTATIONS OF DECEMBER 11 TO
17 OF LAST YEAR HEAVILY SPONSORED BY PRO AI PROGRAM
PARTNERS I REFER YOU TO THE FREE HAND OUT AT THE LIBRARY
ONE CITY ONE BOOK BROCHURE. DR. LEE IS A WONDERFUL
SCIENTIST AND PIONEER OF A.I. AND WHILE VOCAL ABOUT THE
IMPORTANCE OF HUMAN CENTERED, I CITED BY JEFF HINTON PALEY IS
NOT CONSIDERED AN ALARMIST OR HUMOR.
>> ARTIFICIAL GENERAL INTELLIGENCE THEY BELIEVE POSES
AND EXISTENTIAL THREAT TO HUMANITY.
WHAT DOES EXISTENTIAL MEAN? THE DISTINCT POSSIBILITY THAT
THIS FRONTIER TECHNOLOGY TECHNOLOGY THAT IF BUILT WOULD
SURPASS HUMANS NOT ONLY IN INTELLIGENCE BUT
IN CAPABILITY AS WELL CAPABILITIES WHICH WOULD ALLOW
AI'S AGENTS TO PURSUE THEIR OWN AIMS AND GOALS AIMS AND GOALS
WHICH WILL BE OUT OF ALIGNMENT WITH HUMAN NEEDS HUMAN VALUES,
OUR PRIORITIES. AS STEPHEN HAWKINS WARNED US,
THIS SUPERIOR INTELLIGENCE WOULD SUPERSEDE US MEANING TAKE
US OUT MORE. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
. ARE THERE ANY OTHER INDIVIDUALS
WHO WOULD LIKE TO PROVIDE PUBLIC COMMENT?
PLEASE COME FORWARD. THERE ARE NO.
THIS IS WHERE THIS IS GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
YET DO WE HAVE A SLIDE DECK FROM LAST WEEK?
I KNOW I MESSAGED THE NO WE DO NOT.
OKAY SO THEN LET ME SEE IF I CAN TRY TO BRING IT UP ON MY
PHONE. >> OKAY.
I'M GOING TO SWITCH START THE SPEAKERS TIME.
OKAY. LET'S SEE IF IT WORKS AS A
BACKUP. YES.
IS THAT OKAY? OKAY.
HI. MY NAME IS JESSICA PASCOE.
HERE'S MY CREDENTIALS. OKAY.
THERE'S MORE ON OUR BRAND AMBASSADOR AS WELL.
I VOLUNTEER AND A FASHION DESIGNER.
SO WE DID TALK ABOUT THE FIXING THE OVERLAPPING OF BUS ROUTES.
OKAY. >> IT DOESN'T LOOK THAT GOOD
RIGHT HERE BECAUSE OF THE MINIMUM.
>> I'M PAUSING YOUR TIME. THERE'S NO ELECTIONEERING.
THIS IS ELECTION DAYS. SO IF THERE'S ANY
ELECTIONEERING THAT YOU'RE DOING, IT'S NOT YOUR COMMENTS.
>> IT'S NOT AS WHILE FIXING THE BUS RIDES AND WE'RE GOING TO BE
TALKING ABOUT. >> I KNOW THERE WAS A
DISCUSSION ABOUT MAKING HOUSING STABILITY THE OVERSIGHT
COMMITTEE FUND AND HOW WE WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT THOSE
MEETINGS WERE NOT CANCELED ANYMORE.
RECENTLY THEY HAVE BEEN CANCELED AND WE JUST WANT TO
MAKE SURE THAT THOSE MEETINGS DON'T TAKE PLACE.
>> WE ALSO I KNOW THERE WAS THE S.F. DRUG FREE HOUSING MANDATE
THAT OCCURRED. RIGHT.
IF THAT IS THE CASE, I HAD TO GET PAST WHICH I DIDN'T BELIEVE
IT DID. THEN COULD WE PLEASE PUT SOME
CONDITIONS ON THAT BECAUSE THIS COULD BE PRETTY COSTLY AND ALSO
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE'RE ASSESSING THE RIGHT PEOPLE
AND THAT PEOPLE ARE USING SUBSTANCES AND A WORKPLACE
AND THAT THERE'S BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT PEOPLE DOING IT
OUTSIDE ON THE STREET AND WE DON'T WANT TO PUT PEOPLE
IN PRISON. >> WE WANT THEM TO GET MENTAL
HEALTH INSTEAD. >> THE OTHER ISSUE WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT HIS CONSUMER PROTECTIONS AND WE'RE ALSO
GOING TO TALK ABOUT VISION CARE AND SO ALL OF OUR DENTAL CARE
WE NEED MORE FUNDING. >> PLEASE SET ME UP IF YOU NEED
TO. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
SEEN NO OTHER INDIVIDUALS COMING FORWARD FOR PUBLIC
COMMENT, MR. PRESIDENT? >> ALL RIGHT.
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE
FOUR ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA ITEMS 51
AND 52 ITEMS 51 AND 52 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT
COMMITTEE REFERENCE. A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED
FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE.
ANY SUPERVISOR MAY REQUIRE RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE
TO GO TO COMMITTEE. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE
ROLL ON THESE ITEMS. >> MY NAME IS 51 AND 52.
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR OF DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN MANDOLIN I
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SOLDER SOLDER I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR WANG WANG I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EITHER
TONIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED MADAM
CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS?
>> WE HAVE NO IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS TODAY COULD YOU PLEASE
READ THE IN MEMORIAM? >> YES.
TODAY'S MEETING WILL BE ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE
FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR MELGAR
AND PRESIDENT MANDOLIN FOR THE LATE MR. ANTHONY TONY FAZIO
AND ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR MELGAR FOR THE LATE MR. GEORGE
XIONG XING LIM AND ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR CHAN AND SUPERVISOR
WONG FOR THE LATE MR. MICHAEL DURAND.
>> COLLEAGUES THAT BRINGS US TO THE END OF OUR AGENDA, MADAM
CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS BEFORE US TODAY?
>> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS FOR TODAY.
THANK YOU. >> WE ARE ADJOURNED.
>> ASAPH GOV TV SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT TELEVISION